<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Kevon Cheung</title>
        <description>Kevon Cheung - Kevon Cheung</description>
        <link>https://kevoncheung.com</link>
        <link>https://kevoncheung.com</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2020-12-21T07:18:59+08:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2020-12-21T07:18:59+08:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>How to Know If Your Startup Idea Is Worthwhile</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about the next big idea that matches or even beats Airbnb, Netflix, and Uber, then you’re on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs have to keep generating ideas because you never know which one will stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the founding stories of these successful startups were over simplified and glorified. Most of us would never hear about how many ideas and failed validations these founders had to go through in landing to this one business model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to talk about here is: validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of years, mainly because of the Lean Startup movement, a lot of us founders are obsessed with &lt;a href=&quot;/customer-interviews-traps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;talking to users&lt;/a&gt; and finding ways to quickly validate ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-why-i-wrote-this-article&quot;&gt;So, why I wrote this article&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I’m a big fan of talking to people for validation, but the world of founders often jump to this “user interview” step immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that there is a big missing step before founders actually talk to people. Many of them miss it, some of them ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we founders go out to talk to users to discover whether they have “the problem” we’re thinking, we usually already have a rough solution in mind. A lot of wise entrepreneurs advise us not to, but trust me, we still do because we love coming up with solutions as humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we already have this “solution” in mind, we should be evaluating whether this idea is worth pursuing before all the hard work of finding and talking to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this important? Because not every problem is worth solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a tough lesson for me to share because it was one of those moments I couldn’t believe I actually made such a rookie mistake. So I want this to be a guiding principle for me and other founders to evaluate new startup ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-story-of-toasty&quot;&gt;The story of Toasty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran a startup called Toasty for 18 months in 2019-2020. The whole startup was built upon my vision of how we could improve human interactions with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the journey, we pivoted once because we knew our idea and direction was bad, then we pivoted again because of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this post is about the first 6 months of Toasty, before our first pivot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built a matchmaking platform for conference-goers to screen and set up meetings with each other before the actual date. The goal was to enhance their networking experience so that it was worthwhile to spend days at the conference, especially when tickets were so expensive or if attendees traveled overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-shanghai.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toasty in Shanghai&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Here is us traveling to Shanghai for the first conference that used Toasty! We wanted to be there to observe and talk to end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toasty's matchmaking app&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;The web app was beautifully designed to allow any attendee to see who else was going to the conference and set up meetings beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-we-come-up-with-this-idea&quot;&gt;How did we come up with this idea?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, we had zero idea about “the problem” and “the solution”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran about &lt;a href=&quot;/customer-interviews-traps&quot;&gt;a dozen user interviews&lt;/a&gt; in the conference and exhibition space and we could see a trend emerging. Most organizers were searching for new technologies that could level up the attendee’s experience. A good percentage of them had started using different products in the market but were not so happy about them and the outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We researched the space and the competitors and confirmed that there weren’t many competitors in the space, but for the few existing players, we thought they were doing fairly well, built a solid brand, and had grown their team to about 30 people in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these data points, we jumped in without thinking too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 months later, after working with conferences around Asia, I made the decision to pivot our entire direction to work on a new product. I didn’t see how this matchmaking platform could be sustainable to be a solid venture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was one of the toughest calls I had to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-web.png&quot; alt=&quot;Toasty's matchmaking web platform&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Toasty analyzed everyone's profile and recommended people you should meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-learned-about-this-business-model&quot;&gt;What we learned about this business model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the decision to pivot, I took some time to consolidate the learnings and here is a summary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sales-cycle-is-long&quot;&gt;Sales cycle is long&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-salescycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sales cycle is long&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;November is too early to talk about a conference in March next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professional conference organizers typically host 1 to 10 conferences a year, depending on the scale of each one. Most of them don’t think about the operations or experience until the last few months. They kicked off marketing pretty early though. This means the sales cycle is long (2-3 months) for a contract size that is not that big (low four digitsUSD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;frequency-of-usage-is-super-low&quot;&gt;Frequency of usage is super low&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since conferences don’t happen very often, the need of using a matchmaking platform is super low, from once a year to a few times a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buyers-operators-and-end-users-are-three-different-groups-of-people&quot;&gt;Buyers, operators, and end users are three different groups of people&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marketing/experience department search and compare different software options. The operations department handles the logistics of the business matchmaking. And finally, the conference attendees use the software. When the buyer and user isn’t the same person, the chance of having a failed product experience skyrocketed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zero-viral-effect&quot;&gt;Zero viral effect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end users (attendees) are exposed to our matchmaking platform once (during the conference week), and after the conference, our product is completely out of everyone’s mind. The likelihood for someone to talk and share with another person (organizers or attendees) is very low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-off-payment-term&quot;&gt;One-off payment term&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-payment.png&quot; alt=&quot;One-off payment term&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;One-off payment is also hard to collect. Here they just never paid us 50% of the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it is not a SaaS subscription platform but a B2B platform, organizers pay a deposit and then the remaining payment after the conference is done. Then for the next conference in months or a year, it is likely that another person would be in charge of running the show. Pitch once, sell once. Not scalable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;market-size-is-small&quot;&gt;Market size is small&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a naive assumption that because it is a software platform, it would be okay to have a small local market. However, the matchmaking platform actually comes with a lot of other parts, such as on-site logistics, promotion, table arrangement, technical support, etc. Even if we could work this out and serve all the conferences in Asia, this is just not a big market, and it is not growing fast at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;matchmaking-is-not-top-of-the-organizers-mind&quot;&gt;Matchmaking is not top of the organizer’s mind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-priorities.png&quot; alt=&quot;Matchmaking is not top of the organizer's mind&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Keynote and Sponsors make the conference, the other things are all icing on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, they want it and they look for it. But when we dug deeper into the hierarchy of priorities from the organizer’s point of view, these other things are top of their mind: ticket sales, sponsors, booths, speakers, or even the coffee corner. An enhancement of experience using technology? “I’ll think about it when I have time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;willingness-to-pay&quot;&gt;Willingness to pay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though they want it, the time constraint of hosting a conference and that matchmaking being a low priority, they’re always looking for the cheaper solution out there to fill the need and save money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;non-existent-feedback-loop&quot;&gt;Non-existent feedback loop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to growing a startup product is to collect a ton of feedback to improve iteratively. Most of the buyers are not on-site at the matchmaking site, so they cannot offer any feedback. And attendees only get to use our platform for 1-2 days, so it is extremely difficult to follow up to get their feedback as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-hindsight-this-was-a-terrible-idea&quot;&gt;In hindsight, this was a terrible idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-matchmaking-hindsight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toasty's matchmaking is a terrible idea&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Waving goodbye to our first product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this is an impossible idea since a few companies have built a pretty successful business around this niche. It can be a business, just not one that could grow fast and delight a lot of people. It could work in 2015, not 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has changed a lot, now we wouldn’t want to work on this type of idea because the cost is high, growth is slow, and product iteration is extremely lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When competition in each segment is fierce, we must pick ideas that have a better chance of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So reflecting back, I came up with this list to help me evaluate future ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscription&quot;&gt;
	&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; data-uid=&quot;c2f0551d65&quot; src=&quot;https://kevon.ck.page/c2f0551d65/index.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-id-evaluate-my-future-startup-ideas-especially-for-b2b-saas&quot;&gt;How I’d evaluate my future startup ideas (especially for B2B SaaS)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-my-idea-part-of-a-global-trend&quot;&gt;1. Is my idea part of a global trend?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is much better to ride with the wave than to go against it. Zapier played right in the global trend of booming Marketing Technology when they started in 2011. What did they do? They connected all these platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/zapier-martech-landscape-2011-2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Matchmaking is not top of the organizer's mind&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;
	Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://saasmarketer.io/saas-partnership-strategy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SaaS Marketer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-the-product-easy-to-use-can-users-self-onboard&quot;&gt;2. Is the product easy to use? Can users self-onboard?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes sure the rate of growth can be exponential. A product that raises the least confusing questions in the user’s mind wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-it-easy-for-people-to-tell-their-colleagues-or-friends-can-they-try-it-out-immediately&quot;&gt;3. Is it easy for people to tell their colleagues or friends? Can they try it out immediately?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment right after “word of mouth”, when someone just hear about your product from another person, is the best timing to capture interest. They should be able to try out right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-long-is-the-time-to-value-or-aha-moment-can-users-use-it-in-seconds-minutes-or-days-and-weeks&quot;&gt;4. How long is the time to value or AHA moment? Can users use it in seconds, minutes, or days and weeks?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shorter time to value, the more likely for users to fall in love with the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-frequency-of-use-is-it-daily-weekly-monthly-or-annually&quot;&gt;5. What is the frequency of use? Is it daily, weekly, monthly, or annually?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more frequently they use the product, the more likely a habit will be formed, leading to higher stickiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-are-the-players-right-now-how-big-are-they&quot;&gt;6. Who are the players right now? How big are they?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tricky one. Without competitors, I’d question the demand for the space. With fast-growing competitors, I’d question the disadvantage. With a number of companies around 20-30 employees, I’d question the growth potential of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-i-build-a-10x-product-in-this-space-do-i-and-the-co-founders-have-the-background-and-expertise-to-create-a-significantly-better-product-than-everyone-else&quot;&gt;7. Can I build a 10x product in this space? Do I and the co-founders have the background and expertise to create a significantly better product than everyone else?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not 10x better, then there is no point in working on this idea because it is not convincing enough to acquire users. A 10% better product will have a super hard time asking users to form new habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-easy-is-it-to-get-to-the-target-audience-how-big-is-the-market&quot;&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;How easy is it to get to the target audience? How big is the market?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E.g. restaurant is a terrible audience to go after. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/build-something-cool/my-cofounder-said-i-love-what-were-doing-and-we-shut-down-our-startup-80d5e710c2b2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See here&lt;/a&gt;) If it requires salespeople to go door-to-door to get to the audience, the idea won’t fly. Also, after focusing on a niche audience, it must be possible to expand to other groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;over-to-you&quot;&gt;Over to you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a founder, it is your role to evaluate an idea and the relevant hypotheses before wasting resources on building it, or even just researching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assume -&amp;gt; Validate -&amp;gt; Build -&amp;gt; Feedback. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now with the number of #NoCode products out there, it is so easy for founders to run validations quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, after the hard lesson here, we pivoted to a product that was part of the global trend, easy to use, fast to spread, and quick to value. &lt;a href=&quot;https://toasty.ai/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toasty&lt;/a&gt; is now a video meeting platform focused on collaboration and engagement and is getting a lot more users than the matchmaking platform. A sidenote, I stepped down from my CEO role in Oct 2020 and Eric Tsang is now leading the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap this up, I’ve put these 8 questions onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/startup-idea-worthwhile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this Google Sheet&lt;/a&gt; so you can clone and answer them honestly about your idea and see whether you still want to pursue it afterward. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/startup-idea-worthwhile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to download it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/validating-startup-ideas</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/validating-startup-ideas</guid>
                <pubDate>2020-12-12T11:18:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>This Goal-Setting Template Helped Me Hit My Goal in 14 Days</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last 9 months during COVID-19, I was insanely unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before then, I had been exercising regularly through my routine of running and cycling. And I enjoyed getting out for both fresh air and sweat. But ever since COVID-19 became a pandemic, and our team moved to working from home, then my wife became pregnant, suddenly I found myself spending the majority of my time at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was running an investor-backed startup called Toasty as the CEO, and there was tremendous pressure on me to make it work. “Giving the best I can” was my mantra at that time, which meant sacrificing other things in order to give everything I had to Toasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was unhealthy because I stopped going outside to exercise, fearing that I could expose myself to COVID-19 and affect my pregnant wife. But more importantly, I started dwelling on my work at Toasty and I worked from 7am to 11pm 3 days a week. I was “in the zone”. I made Toasty the highest priority and decided to defer other things. With the amount of pressure, I also ate and drank a lot to ease my stress, completely breaking my calorie quota each day. And because of that, I also became lazier to exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day, I put on an old t-shirt and headed out. In the elevator, I looked into the mirror and couldn’t help to shout in my mind “What happened to me?” My belly was unbearable! I knew I was becoming a father, but that didn’t mean I had to pick up a dadbod. I was embarrassed by myself and I knew I had to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then embarked on a 14 days challenge to put my belly back in shape. I didn’t know if 14 days would be enough to see a drastic body change, but it was a timeframe that I could comfortably accept. I also didn’t want a trainer or coach, I knew I could do this myself.  So in this period, I focused on 4 things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running&lt;/strong&gt; - I had been a runner and I knew cardio was important to get the body going&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pumping HIIT&lt;/strong&gt; - the best way to lose fat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eating clean&lt;/strong&gt; - a proper diet was equally important to all the exercises&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding protein&lt;/strong&gt; - a high protein intake can boost my metabolism, which means burning more calories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-result&quot;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My belly went from 87cm to 82cm in 4 weeks, and then to 80cm in 2 more weeks. A 9% reduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My bodyweight went from 154 lbs to 149 lbs. A mere 3.2% lighter, that’s perfect as I didn’t want to lose too much weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14 days turned into 6 weeks, and it is still going today. The success of the past 6 weeks made me realize the power of goal-setting, progression, and motivation. And I started thinking about why it went so well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to answer some of my inner questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did a 14 days challenge turn into a 6 weeks thing and it is still going on in my life right now?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What were the key ingredients or secret formulas that made it relatively easy to achieve my goal?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was different about this challenge vs my previous set goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sweat&quot;&gt;The sweat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at what I did in the last 6 weeks compared to the first 9 months of 2020. This is my running calendar on Strava.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Jan to Sep, on average I ran less than 2 hours a month, and I rarely did any exercise other than running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/kevon-running-calendar-2020.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kevon's Training Calendar 2020&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from mid-Oct, I’ve boosted up to at least 10-13 hours of running in a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started following some Youtube videos for 20-min HIIT, I did it on average 4-5 times a week. This meant for at least half the week, I ran and did HIIT on the same day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eating wise, I ordered calorie-controlled meal plans so that I could burn more than I took in each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/kevon-diet.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kevon's Diet&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, I put up a piece of paper and recorded my weight and waist every morning. I forgot to do so on some days. And as you can see, I was drunk one day (lol) so I didn’t manage to exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/kevon-progress.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kevon's Progress Tracking&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-it-work-the-5-magical-ingredients&quot;&gt;Why did it work? The 5 magical ingredients.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-gave-myself-an-achievable-timeframe&quot;&gt;1. I gave myself an achievable timeframe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14 days is a great length to push for change. It is long enough to develop habits and routines, yet it is short enough for me to see the finish line. It is important for me to know that there is an end to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-wasnt-thinking-about-my-end-goal&quot;&gt;2. I wasn’t thinking about my end goal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My end goal was to lose my big belly. But to focus on that wasn’t going to get me there, so I didn’t think about it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, every day I woke up, I was thinking about going for a run, doing a 20-min HIIT, and what I was going to eat. These things were top of my mind, not my end goal which was out of my control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-made-this-top-of-my-mind&quot;&gt;3. I made this top of my mind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so embarrassed about my belly that this whole challenge became top of my mind during this period. Every day I was thinking about it, doing it, and observing results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was immersed into the experience. And I was having fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-measured-daily-progress&quot;&gt;4. I measured daily progress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see at the sheet above, I recorded my bodyweight and waist on a piece of paper first thing every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not a pure tracking system. This was a mental system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this was the first thing I did every morning, I was drawn to being impressed by myself by my consistency and perseverance, and I got even more excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-bragged-about-myself&quot;&gt;5. I bragged about myself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best of all five. Bragging was a big motivation. In other words, I called it “celebrating small wins”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I pushed for these 7am runs and seemingly disgusting meals, I had people around me wondering how I did that. And with results coming in, I got to show off to families/friends about the tremendous progress I was making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscription&quot;&gt;
	&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; data-uid=&quot;c2f0551d65&quot; src=&quot;https://kevon.ck.page/c2f0551d65/index.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-role-did-my-mind-play-in-all-these&quot;&gt;What role did my mind play in all these?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I internalized the 5 points above, even though they mapped to a fitness goal in this case, the same formula could be applied to all sorts of goal setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure a lot of you reading this will now go “This is just like other frameworks I’ve tried before, but they never worked.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re right, it is similar to say SMART Goals. But here I want you to realize one thing, the 5 ingredients are all pointing at one critical factor in achieving my goal: my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see that everything I did here was directing my mind to the right mindset by setting up the appropriate cues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I set 14 days to tell my mind that it was short and I could easily do it. Or I told my mind to not think about things I couldn’t control. Or I forced my mind to look at progress on a piece of paper every day. Or I bragged to make my mind feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I realized from these 6 weeks was that developing habits and routines weren’t enough because, without goals, they didn’t mean anything. When my belly got down to 80cm, I lost about 40% of the motivation to get myself out of bed to run. I needed a new goal when the last goal is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the formula works only if we keep setting short-term goals using the 5 ingredients and keep repeating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned that a lot about achieving goals comes down to how you engineer the small details to cue your own mind. With the right cue, you do the right things. When you do the right things, you make things happen in your control. When you make enough of these things happen, your ultimate goal is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t overwhelm myself with too many short-term goals at the same time, because I think it is just impossible to have so many “top of minds”. To me, combining career goals, fitness goals, family goals, and mental goals, having 4 at the same time is the limit. Of course, as we practice, we might be able to increase that number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-why-did-goal-setting-fail-for-me-previously&quot;&gt;And why did goal setting fail for me previously?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve set many goals for myself in my life. Some I achieved, and some I failed. I used to love putting up my new year solutions on my blog, so let’s take a look at what I set in the past years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/kevon-2019-goals.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kevon's 2019 Goals&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my goals for 2019, and looking back, they’re large and vague goals, they’re things I couldn’t control. And you bet it, it was out of my mind after about a week into 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, I will abandon the whole concept of new year resolutions. Instead, I will give myself loads of 14 days challenges in different areas of my life, achieve them, and celebrate small wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-can-get-an-easy-start-now&quot;&gt;You can get an easy start now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge for you right now is that you understand you have to guide your mind when you set new goals, but to apply a model like this seems like a lot of work, and you don’t know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like starting anything new, I recommend starting small and then celebrating it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal here is to have a successful story about achieving a goal in 14 days. Once you get there, then you’ll naturally expand in your own ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get you started, I have this framework set up so &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/my14dayschallenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;you can clone the Google Sheet for free here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/my14dayschallenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/kevon-goal-setting.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kevon's Goal Setting Framework&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/my14dayschallenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/my14dayschallenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; in, and get started today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can guarantee you that something good is going to come out after these 14 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like a second pair of eyes to look through what you have noted down, I’d be happy to review and give you some feedback. Just &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevon69/status/1336443799455711232&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hit me up on this Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; and we can connect and chat!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/goal-setting</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/goal-setting</guid>
                <pubDate>2020-12-08T09:24:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Understanding SEO as a First-time Founder</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As a founder, you hear about SEO but all the articles out there are crazily technical. You want to know why you should care about SEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And believe it or not. Most founders focus on product much more than marketing in the early days. This is because intuitively, we’re inclined to work out a solution before we drive traction. But this is not going to work in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this article is for first-time founders to understand the importance of doing marketing early and how SEO plays a key role in building up sustainable traction for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch out - this is not a detailed SEO article for technical SEO marketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was running Toasty, a video collab platform, in the last 18 months, I made a mistake of putting 6.5 headcounts in product and leaving half of myself as the only marketing/growth person to build awareness and generate traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result? Imbalanced and slow growth. So I understand first-hand why you should start your marketing as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also going to break down based on what I wished I knew as a founder back then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why should you invest in SEO?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is SEO? (Very brief as this is not a technical article)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When to invest in SEO?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How frequently do you publish content?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you just publish and wait?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re a founder and you don’t have time, what’s the best way to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-invest-in-seo&quot;&gt;Why should you invest in SEO?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Toasty, we needed awareness and traffic. I was hustling everywhere like a baby trying to get attention from his parents. I wrote articles, I distributed them on Slack groups, I posted on social media, I bought ads, I ran campaigns to capture emails …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was difficult. With so much effort, we saw traffic going up steadily but slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day, our blog traffic started to rise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And soon, it tripled month to month. Then it doubled and doubled again. What happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/toasty-blog-traffic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: Toasty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-break-down-the-traffic&quot;&gt;Let’s break down the traffic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the start, no matter how hard we shared our articles, we got hundreds of views only (see Sep-Dec 2019).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We pushed harder and achieved 3,000+ in Mar and Apr 2020, then we lost our junior marketer and stopped actively distributing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When SEO kicked in in Jul 2020, we grew solely on organic traffic due to lack of manpower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was dream come true!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More traffic meant we had a lot more room to run experiments, to grow our user base, and to improve our conversions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-was-going-on&quot;&gt;What was going on?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First let me summarized a few of our main channels in the early days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slack communities&lt;/strong&gt; - we met people, built relationships, and distributed articles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bought Google ads&lt;/strong&gt; - quick and easy but didn’t yield results&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn engagement&lt;/strong&gt; - built up our audience, worked extremely well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn cold outreach&lt;/strong&gt; - for customer discovery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email marketing&lt;/strong&gt; - to stay in touch with pre-launch waitlist and our user list&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content marketing + SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - I was a big believer that one day it will pay off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this entire period, Jul 2019 to Oct 2020, I was doing marketing and growth with a one freelance writer. In a few months on and off, I had a junior team member to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the list above, most of the marketing tactics required consistent labor week in, week out. Whenever my attention as CEO was diverted or when the junior marketer resigned, we had a big gap in the marketing system. And our website and blog traffic took a big hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content &amp;amp; SEO, on the other hand, are tactics that once you put it out there, it is evergreen and doesn’t require your daily attention. You still need to build strategies around it, but the core of it is sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay a side thing. As I have a newborn coming in 5 weeks. I was thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toys are like ads.&lt;/strong&gt; They’re expensive. They boost happiness in the short-term, but soon they’ll be forgotten.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books are like content &amp;amp; SEO.&lt;/strong&gt; They’re inexpensive. The knowledge acquired is sustainable, and it can always be revisited.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ha! So I prefer to buy books for my daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-seo&quot;&gt;What is SEO?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a founder and you do not know about SEO, I urge you to study about it asap. Don’t ever fully rely on someone else to execute this for you, you need to understand how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the most important parts are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt; - pick relevant keywords to your business and focus on them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-site technicals&lt;/strong&gt; - make sure your website is optimized for SEO technically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backlinks&lt;/strong&gt; - build partnerships and have them link to you to boost your credibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content&lt;/strong&gt; - you can do well in SEO, but if your content sucks, you’ll go nowhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the technical SEO articles you should read:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://backlinko.com/hub/seo/what-is-seo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Backlinko - What is SEO?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://backlinko.com/seo-this-year&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Backlinko - The Definitive Guide To SEO In 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscription&quot;&gt;
	&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; data-uid=&quot;c2f0551d65&quot; src=&quot;https://kevon.ck.page/c2f0551d65/index.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-to-invest-in-seo&quot;&gt;When to invest in SEO?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew content and SEO would be keys to our growth, so I started on Day One. Huge mistake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hadn’t validated our problem statement enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were still &lt;a href=&quot;/customer-interviews-traps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;doing customer discovery interviews&lt;/a&gt;, we had a tiny sense of a direction, and immediately I started creating content. A few months down the road, we decided to pivot, and all the content became garbage. We literally had to remove all of them from our blog because they were irrelevant to the new direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But … if you look at the stats above. You can see it took us a long 6-8 months before SEO kicked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So do we start early or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is that you start content &amp;amp; SEO as early as you validate the problem hypothesis. You don’t need to validate the solution yet, because you can always produce content covering a broader scope to focus on “generating early awareness”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, your product development and content marketing &amp;amp; SEO can go in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-frequently-do-you-publish-content&quot;&gt;How frequently do you publish content?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, you don’t need to be a machine to produce content too frequently. It is better to be strategic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You want to know the keywords that you want to focus on. Since you’re new in the market, go for longtail keywords that have reasonable volume and less competition. You should also try keywords that interest your target audience but have little to do with your product, this way you can attract different groups of audiences. Diversify!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Just like everything else. Being consistent is the priority. 1 post every 2 weeks? Fine&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your content has to be top notch that the readers should say in their mind “Oh! This is so useful!” Also, many people make the mistakes of not having a clear CTA in the post, don’t do that. Capture their emails or get them to your website, whatever the next step is in the funnel&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-just-publish-and-wait&quot;&gt;Do you just publish and wait?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No … I did that and nothing happened! Never just sit and wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing you take away from this article, remember this. We spent 80% producing + 20% distributing, and it was a huge mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Content should really be 40% producing and 60% distributing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of creating content like making scrambled eggs. You make them, but you have to EAT them to get the nutrition (result).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s even better? You can also share the eggs with your family. Cook once, 4 people enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also another key for content marketing. Make sure you keep recycling and remixing content to maximize results. Here is &lt;a href=&quot;https://rosssimmonds.com/content-distribution/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the article that inpsired our team&lt;/a&gt; to level up our game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-covid-story-about-distribution&quot;&gt;A COVID story about distribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early early 2020, we found 3 Slack communities to be an amazing way to share our content. We posted our newly published articles and easily got hundreds of views per piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then COVID happened globally in March 2020, and suddenly each Slack group was flooded with people who were stuck at home and thinking about how to do marketing online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more articles are being posted everyday, and yes, no one read them anymore because it was so overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I cannot tell you how you can distribute your content effectively. Just remember, always go to where your target audience is, and do it creatively before other people figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re blindly going to Product Hunt, Slack groups, and just post and wait, good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;youre-a-founder-and-you-dont-have-time-whats-the-best-way-to-do-this&quot;&gt;You’re a founder and you don’t have time, what’s the best way to do this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first-time founder, you have a million things on your plate, you don’t have time to create content yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tactic was to write the first few pieces myself to set the tone and style, then hire someone better at writing to replace me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for the first 4 weeks, I wrote 4 pieces myself. And I also started looking for a freelance writer and a graphic designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is almost impossible to know if this person is the right fit until you try it out, so I suggest you to work on 1-2 piece together and see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hiring-and-collaborating-with-writer--designer&quot;&gt;Hiring and collaborating with writer &amp;amp; designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For writer, I recommend setting a standard of let’s say 1,500 words per articles for a fixed price and be okay with less words. This is because you want to emphasize quality over length. Trust your writer. For designer, hourly rate makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need someone, happy to connect to the ones I enjoy working with. Just say hi on Twitter/email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it comes the system I built on Trello board (after working smoothly with them):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I studied our own niche and relevant keywords and shared with the freelance writer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We discussed on a high level, and she listed down 4 topics she would write for the next month.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When she finished one piece, she reached out to the designer directly for visuals of the post.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the piece is finalized, I’d review before an agreed published deadline, and writer would post it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a founder, you have to focus on the strategy and build system to get things done. But, I’d always suggest you to kick off something yourself to set the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the Trello board as reference or more details on how this system works, say hi on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevon69/status/1333744350560276482&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this tweet-thread&lt;/a&gt;. Happy to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-recap&quot;&gt;To recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start marketing early along with product development as soon as you validate the problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invest in content &amp;amp; SEO early and do it consistently, it is a sustainable channel with high ROI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That being said, you still have to work on your other marketing channels (short-term). Don’t ever just focus on content &amp;amp; SEO (long-term). Short and long tactics should play cohesively&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once things are initiated, build a system to create leverage for yourself. You’ll realize you can offload a lot to freelancers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-was-inspired-by-these-companies&quot;&gt;I was inspired by these companies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buffer&quot;&gt;Buffer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buffer was the pioneer in content a decade ago in 2010. They figured out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yesoptimist.com/buffer-content-marketing-strategy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;guest blogging&lt;/a&gt; could bring in large volume of sustainable traffic and, of course, revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/buffer-revenue.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.baremetrics.com/stats/mrr#start_date=2012-12-01&amp;amp;end_date=2018-01-22&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Baremetrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zapier&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Growth Lever 7 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://saasmarketer.io/saas-partnership-strategy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How Zapier Grew To $50m ARR Fully Remote&lt;/a&gt;. They understood how people searched and capitalized with their “list post”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/zapier-seo-growth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://saasmarketer.io/saas-partnership-strategy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SaaS Marketer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;canva&quot;&gt;Canva&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.growthmanifesto.com/canva-growth-study&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;technical side of SEO&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll learn how smart they were in structuring their website, choosing keywords, and making the pages ranked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/canva-organic-traffic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.growthmanifesto.com/canva-growth-study&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Growth Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/seo-first-time-founders</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/seo-first-time-founders</guid>
                <pubDate>2020-11-29T09:24:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>You Should Avoid These Customer Interviews Traps</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As a founder or product leader, are you obsessed with user interviews?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You likely have already read about the best practices to do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But having done 200+ user interviews in the last 18 months, I discovered that following the best practices wasn’t enough, there were these frustrating traps that I learned to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are the top 4 for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trap-1---i-was-overdoing-these-interviews-and-lost-sight-of-the-meaning&quot;&gt;Trap #1 - I was overdoing these interviews and lost sight of the meaning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been a big fan of “staying close to your users” and I took that to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to potential users and existing users became a routine of mine when I was building Toasty. The more I did, the less time I had to prepare and analyze. Which meant at some point I wasn’t even validating any hypothesis at these interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lost the meaning of these interviews and was doing it for the sake of “staying close”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With an overwhelming plate as the CEO, I lost my consciousness in product discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As I frequently met with potential and existing users, I lost track of whom I was speaking to and for what purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned. I needed to be clear of its objective before setting up an interview. And technically I only needed 5-10 interviews each time to validate one hypothesis and should have moved on to the next hypothesis regardless of the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trap-2---people-were-just-so-nice&quot;&gt;Trap #2 - People were just so nice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other reason I loved talking to people was that 90% of the people I met were amazing. They were generous in sharing and genuine in helping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was good, but also bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got distracted by phrases like “what you’re doing is interesting”, “I love your idea.” and “I will definitely try your product.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took their words at face value and got excited … and then I was blindsided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People say “what users say and what they do are different”. It is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that we should have excluded their ideas and opinions from the interviews. What was more important was the facts. “I love your idea” didn’t help with the validation; “I was doing X to solve Y” provided more insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned that it was better to look for facial expression, body language, and actual product usage to gauge whether they’re interested. If they show excitement, curiosity, urgency, or if they immediately check out or sign up for our product and start using it, then it is a sign that they’re interested. Otherwise, despite all the kind words, they’re really not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscription&quot;&gt;
	&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; data-uid=&quot;c2f0551d65&quot; src=&quot;https://kevon.ck.page/c2f0551d65/index.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trap-3---never-asked-for-solutions-from-customers&quot;&gt;Trap #3 - Never asked for solutions from customers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry Ford once said, if he had asked his customers for new ideas, they would have told him to create faster horses. He didn’t do that, and he created cars to replace horses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us understand that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I was actually talking to customers, it was a very different story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was perfectly aware that I shouldn’t ask them for ideas (learnings from &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JZ9AUT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Mom Test&lt;/a&gt;, my favorite user interview book). We also had our own solution in mind already. But it was extremely hard to stay away from their constant “feature requests”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people learned more about Toasty, it was natural for them to tell me how they would use Toasty only if we had A, B, and C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I heard that, I got sidetracked. These ideas were tempting as they would make our product better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I logged these “feature ideas” for our product team. But, we never acted immediately on them. We waited for more similar patterns before we designed and developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we knew how to handle these requests. The reality was since we were searching for product/market fit, these feature ideas were really just “small details”. They would make us a 10% better product, but never a 10x better product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to create a successful product (and company), we needed to work on a 10x better product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned. I needed to break down the insights from customers into 2 tracks - 1 being facts and behaviors to lead us to a 10x product, the other 1 being feature ideas for immediate product enhancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trap-4---i-didnt-have-a-proper-post-interview-tactic&quot;&gt;Trap #4 - I didn’t have a proper post-interview tactic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the rules of user interviews is to talk to people from the same segment. This way you can discover common patterns from the same type of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once you get to know them, the best part is they become leads that you can convert when you’re ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was talking to almost a dozen people every week, and I didn’t capitalize on this opportunity to help us generate leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to people, and then we forgot about each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a waste. After all, I had already turned cold leads into warm leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early-stage startups, everything we do has to be super impactful because we are competing against time. One thing should lead to another, creating not linear, but exponential values. There is a concept called “System Thinking” and I plan to write about it later on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned. I should have set up a better plan to follow up with these interviewees, keep them in the loop, and incentivize them beyond the chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-interviews-are-hard&quot;&gt;User interviews are hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you’re dealing with human beings, and each of them thinks differently. And to extract useful insights requires all the important skills like analytical listening and imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, no one could get it right the first time, and I certainly learned it the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some other user interviews traps that you’ve encountered?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/customer-interviews-traps</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/customer-interviews-traps</guid>
                <pubDate>2020-11-22T11:04:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Why No One Reads What You Write: Dissecting Dave Gerhardt's Copywriting</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in March 2020, I was very active on my LinkedIn trying to engage my network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon I realized the engagement numbers weren’t moving at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time looking at the best marketer I knew, Dave Gerhardt, and studied how he did it. And I learned that it all came down to copywriting skills - which I sucked at. I was determined to get that fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-need-to-brush-up-your-copywriting&quot;&gt;Why you need to brush up your copywriting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at the best influencers in the world and how they drive thousands, if not hundreds, of engagement, it is always: can you relate to people quickly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are still used to the traditional form of communication - broadcast a message, people like it or leave it, and we carry on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then social media came along, and it became all about speaking directly to your audiences and have this two-way communication. Now, everyone is a marketing channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best form of communication is still text, believe it or not. That’s where copywriting comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a lot of us don’t take copywriting seriously because it is not easy to spot that you’re not good at it. As long as you can write, you can always produce something. But are people reading it? That’s the billion dollar question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
	&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Copywriting is the most underrated skill. Most people write so they think it’s not hard. There’s not an obvious technical barrier like with coding or oil painting, where you can’t do it and therefore realize there’s skill involved&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Wes Kao (@wes_kao) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wes_kao/status/1328441465073229833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 16, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dave-gerhardts-copywriting-tactics-on-linkedin&quot;&gt;Dave Gerhardt’s copywriting tactics on LinkedIn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend enough time in the marketing world, you must know Dave Gerhardt. He was the VP of Marketing at Drift and now CMO at Privy. He is amazing because he is very different from the other marketing leaders. And you know he is good by looking at his engagement metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how does he write on LinkedIn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He writes like he talks&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He is talking to a very clear audience&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His opening line is very short (8-16 words)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He tells a story (even a personal one)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He shares users’ success stories&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He uses bullet points&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He focuses on one hashtag only&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He injects personality and talks about unrelated things&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He posts consistently&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He speaks the annoying truth&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-look-at-each-one-with-details&quot;&gt;Let’s look at each one with details!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-writes-like-he-talks&quot;&gt;He writes like he talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a lot of us, when we first write marketing copies, somehow we always go for a commercial, robotic type of tone as if that is the golden standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave doesn’t do that. When you read his words, you feel that he is talking to you like a friend on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-6-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-is-talking-to-a-very-clear-audience&quot;&gt;He is talking to a very clear audience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all get greedy and want to speak to a lot of people at once. Dave focuses on marketers and he makes it very clear. Funny enough, by doing this, he naturally attracts other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-1-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;his-opening-line-is-short-8-16-words&quot;&gt;His opening line is short (8-16 words)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to look at his 1st line. The shorter (&amp;lt;10 words), the better. Because no one gives a f about your writing so you only have the 1st line (likely 0.3 seconds) to get their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-7-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-tells-a-story-even-a-personal-one&quot;&gt;He tells a story (even a personal one)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all love reading a story because we’re nosy and we want to find out what happened. Daves always writes as if he is telling a quick bedtime story to his kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-2-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-uses-bullet-points&quot;&gt;He uses bullet points&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one has time, so let’s cut to the chase. Removing words is key in good copywriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-8-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-focuses-on-one-hashtag-only&quot;&gt;He focuses on one hashtag only&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking of using hashtags to bring in views &amp;amp; engagement? It is not quite sustainable and Dave doesn’t care about that. He is persistent on one hashtag only: #marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-9-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscription&quot;&gt;
	&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; data-uid=&quot;c2f0551d65&quot; src=&quot;https://kevon.ck.page/c2f0551d65/index.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-injects-personality-and-talks-about-unrelated-things&quot;&gt;He injects personality and talks about unrelated things&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big one. If copywriting is #1 important, personality is #2. Have some swags and differentiate yourself from the rest. Dave is genuine and fun, and you just want to be his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-10-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-posts-consistently&quot;&gt;He posts consistently&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep an active presence, Dave tweets at least once a day, and posts on LinkedIn every other day if not everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;he-speaks-the-annoying-truth&quot;&gt;He speaks the annoying truth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes the best way to resonate with your audience - get on the same side! Dave points out annoying things he faces in his life/work and it feels like a friend telling you over lunch, so you jump into the conversation. 3,106 reactions and 723 comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-12-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-writing-well-is-not-enough-on-linkedin&quot;&gt;Bonus: writing well is not enough on LinkedIn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not from Dave, but I must bring it up because I see quite a lot of people writing better yet still don’t get the engagement they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to dedicate time to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove irrelevant Linkedin connections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean up your feed by “Unfollow XXX”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you only see relevant connections &amp;amp; your target audience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add or follow more target audience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interact with their posts genuinely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By doing this consistently, you’ll start seeing results coming back to your posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-improved-my-engagement-results&quot;&gt;How I improved my engagement results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, here I’m only able to capture a small part of his mastermind. You’ll learn much more if you follow Dave’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davegerhardt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/davegerhardt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I picked up these tactics from Dave. I put them into practice and saw my engagement numbers go up and up. Within 5 months, I was able to achieve 5-10x growth on my regular LinkedIn posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gerhardt-kevons-results.png&quot; alt=&quot;Engagement Metrics Growing&quot; class=&quot;full-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope these are helpful, and please share with me if you think there are more I should add to this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, I’m starting to write and share my learnings in product &amp;amp; growth. If you enjoy this, I’d appreciate to hear from you so that I can improve. And of course, subscribe below if you want to hear from me again. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/dave-gerhardt-copywriting</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/dave-gerhardt-copywriting</guid>
                <pubDate>2020-11-18T08:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>I Am Giving Back This Year</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A thought came to mind this morning. It is not a new idea because in fact, I’ve been doing it last week without knowing. This new thought is about making 2019 a year to give back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-instance&quot;&gt;First Instance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I stumbled upon the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreenrace.hk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Green Race website&lt;/a&gt; when I saw a friend running with them on a casual Wed night, and I wanted to join. My eyes incidentally landed on the “Volunteer” tab and without overthinking it, I signed up to be a volunteer in their upcoming beach &amp;amp; trail cleanups and also races. Why am I interested in that? I like to read about environmental issues and I have a strong feeling to do something after seeing all the plastic ruining our ocean and beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An anecdote to go along with this. I remembered a few months ago when I was on the street, I chatted with a rep from an NGO and she asked me for monthly donations. Since I have a regular donation to World Vision for a little girl in Ethiopia, I asked for other volunteer opportunities that I can help physically. She mentioned beach and trail cleanups and got me excited. What happened next turned excitement into frustration. She also said I have to be a member in order to participate, which implied I should make a monthly donation. This is frustrating. Why is it so hard trying to help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;second-instance&quot;&gt;Second Instance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I saw on Instagram Story that a college friend is working on some plain HTML. I asked her why. Because no one ever uses plain HTML files anymore. I went on to offer teaching her how to build a Wordpress site for the blog she has been wanting to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been a big “volunteer” person in my life. This year, I am picking up the mindset of giving. It doesn’t matter whether it is for the environment or for the people around me. I get to where I am today because people help me, and I think it is time to give back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/i-am-giving-back-this-year</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/i-am-giving-back-this-year</guid>
                <pubDate>2019-01-29T09:35:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>2018 Year in Review & 2019 Goals</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;2018 was a year to get ready for 2019. Let me tell you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled to invite Lydia to join me into the next phase of our lives and to build our future together - this was an immense milestone and achievement to me. Growing up I told myself I would get married around 32-34 and there was no need to rush. My mindset used to be “let me enjoy the freedom while I can”, but it has evolved. Now my belief is that starting a family creates a solid foundation for me to be “free”, to focus, and to go hard on my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel, for the first time since graduating from university, I felt that I was not making enough progress this year. In the first 5 years from 2012-2017, I was a machine. I worked day and night and weekend. I wanted to go faster, to learn as much as I can, and to achieve something for myself. I wasn’t sure this was what people call a “burn out” or not. Nevertheless, I felt that it was a positive period as I got to reposition myself for the next big thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened-in-2018&quot;&gt;What happened in 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got engaged! I have to say I’m a lucky person to have met Lydia; not just because we’re becoming husband and wife, it is also because we’re in a really, really great relationship. Friends around us continue to ask the two of us questions like - how do you know he/she is the one? How do you have such a good relationship? Do you two even argue? I’m most grateful for our approach and mutual understanding in this relationship, I think that makes all the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compared to 2017, I read slightly more in 2018 (mainly because I only managed to read 6 books in 2017). You can tell from the list that it was a bit all over the place. That’s right, I wanted to diversify my knowledge base instead of only focusing on business/management/leadership books. I learned 2 lessons from reading this year: 1) how to read multiple books at the same time and 2) how to skim through a book for the key highlights instead of reading word to word. These methods actually make me happier and want to read more.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3oMbwiq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lost and Founder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3nhGY7C&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Profit First&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37bLyP7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Do - Purpose - why brands with a purpose do better and matter more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37VSXBh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Four-Hour Work week (Reread)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2IE1aSj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Girl, Wash Your Face&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33XxAP5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Capitalism without Capital (Partial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gCm6pp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Pumpkin Plan (Partial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/344OZoS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Invested&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3m9HaV6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Talk so Kids Will Listen &amp;amp; Listen so Kids Will Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JXhRbM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Principles: Life and Work (Reread)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got better at speaking in front of camera and got slightly more creative. Thanks to my effort to share more on relationship/marriage/parenting through “Uncle Cheung”, I practiced a lot of speaking in front of the camera. At first, it was a nightmare. I was nervous and I couldn’t even go beyond 2 lines. As I filmed myself more, I learned to treat the camera like a friend and to be okay with the imperfect me. Making mistakes is okay, and people actually love to see flaws! In terms of creativity, because I have to plan video topics and content, I have to keep my ideas fresh and different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After being at First Code Academy for close to 4 years, where I became the COO and also the co-founder alongside Michelle, I decided it was time for a change. First Code had been the best time of my career and since I built everything up from the ground with Michelle, it was a very, very difficult decision to make. Seeing a more organized structure in the company compared to 4 years ago and a team of talented members, it was time for me to see what’s out there to continue develop myself to new heights.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I improved my swimming techniques in the first half of 2018, then I got into cycling in the second half. Not that I’m really good at all of them, I just felt self-empowered being able to run, swim, and cycle as a suite.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Near the end of 2018 was fun! I wanted to give myself a short break to rejuvenate and to explore, and video creation and editing have always been a side interest of mine. I spent 2 months learning everything about video editing and YouTube, from filming, to acting, to gaining insights on what people like to watch, to editing, to promoting. There has been a lot to learn and I have a ton of respect to the video creators out there who release videos every week. It looks easy but to put it in the right perspective, it is like making a short movie every week. It is tough. I love sharing my own creation, so I hope to share more down the road about my own experiences starting a family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-going-on-in-2019&quot;&gt;What is going on in 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drive innovation and impact through working with a talented, forward-thinking team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expand my circle through meeting and collaborating with new friends. This is especially true to a small entrepreneurs circle called “The Circle of Ants” that I started a few years ago with a close friend, Johanna. The circle meets once a month to discuss business topics like expansion, marketing, personal branding etc. It is meant to be a small group so we have 5 people in total, and in 2019 I would love to expand it to 8.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop an online course. This has been on my mind for awhile since I run a lot of trainings at First Code Academy, and now that I become familiar with video production, I think it is time. I want to share my experience working my way up at First Code and how everyone can be successful at her company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an amazing wedding in Nov 2019!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This might be the first year I don’t set myself a fitness goal, mainly because there are too many happenings in other areas of my life. I wanted to train for a triathlon or duathlon, but I don’t think this is the year. Anyway, I do have a fitness routine, so I feel okay without setting a goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-world-topics-that-ive-been-thinking-about&quot;&gt;Some world topics that I’ve been thinking about&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raising a kid in the modern days.&lt;/strong&gt; As I learn a lot about building a family and parenting in the end of 2018, I came to realize how difficult it is to raise a kid in modern days. In the past, most mums stayed home to take care of the children. It didn’t matter whether she was educated or not, at least she was able to directly raise her kids and taught them life values. Now, with double-income families, the responsibility of raising kids get passed to the grandparents or the helpers for close to 80-90% of the time during weekday. I am sure grandparents and helpers would take very good care of the baby’s/kid’s daily needs, yet in terms of teaching languages, behaviors, and values, I’m highly doubtful they can get the kid ready for today’s fast-paced world. Yes, I’m sure these kids will turn out okay because to be honest, our parents weren’t that hands on as well. I just wonder what kind of impact this set up will have on our next generations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change, trash, and plastic usage.&lt;/strong&gt; This topic increasingly worries me as more and more news and messages talk about it. World population is growing. Carbon emissions are raising. Climate is getting uncertain. More and more trash are produced and the majority of them goes to the landfills. Plastic is everywhere. I know that we’re getting better and better by finding new energy source, reducing plastic bags and straws, promoting recycling etc., but I don’t know if we’re doing all these fast enough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social media addiction.&lt;/strong&gt; Social media is getting scary because it offers an overwhelming amount of information and it is addicting. I spent quite a lot of time on Instagram and YouTube in 2018, and what did I get from that? I felt closer to people I didn’t hang out in real life because I knew all about their lives through Instagram photos and stories. That sounds weird, so time to turn these off in 2019. Also, I feel that virtual reality world, described in movie Ready Player One, is going to take over our lives at some point. That’s going to be the thing after social media, just a matter of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wraps up my reflection. Cheers to a great 2019 ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/2018-year-in-review-2019-goals</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/2018-year-in-review--2019-goals</guid>
                <pubDate>2019-01-07T10:20:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>2017 Year in Review</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;2017 was definitely a year with big steps. Today I spent some time reflecting on the past year, about First Code, about myself, and about what I could do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-sharing&quot;&gt;Public Sharing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 was a year full of sharing. I spoke at multiple events such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://summit.edtechasia.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EdTech Asia 2017&lt;/a&gt; in Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam, a pre-Rise event in Hong Kong, &lt;a href=&quot;http://singapore.slush.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slush Singapore&lt;/a&gt;, and a bunch of in-house First Code events. All I want at these events is that the auidence has something to take away from my presentation, and so each time I make sure to pick 3 clear points and build my talk around them. I respect speakers who appear well prepared and who care about the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BZOI3Opn4pm/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;8&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.31481481481482% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BZOI3Opn4pm/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pleasure to be at @slushsingapore talking about the next generation of tech natives. I always love to share how 6yo can learn coding because people always find it surprising. The truth is coding is just a method, ultimately it is about developing child&amp;#39;s logical thinking, problem solving, and independent thinking! 👶🏼🙌🏻🎉 #firstcode #appjamming #entrepreneurship #startup #slushsingapore #happening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/kevon/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Kevon Cheung&lt;/a&gt; (@kevon) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-09-19T11:27:55+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 19, 2017 at 4:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-code-academy&quot;&gt;First Code Academy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely proud of First Code this year. Not only were we able to make a huge progress in building a sustainable company, we also developed a number of new leaders on the team and a lot of good practices that will take us far. Although there are many, many challenges to overcome in the near future, I want to be grateful for what we have right now. Being thankful should be a requirement as we continue to strive for excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I’m happy about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Nurturing new leaders on the team and providing the right coaching and support for them to lead&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Becoming more data-oriented, having an end goal in mind all the time&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Having more time dedicated to big picture thinking and planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BaIQoHIBtBa/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;8&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:28.125% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BaIQoHIBtBa/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Happy 4yo Birthday to @first_code !! Every year, we have the same reaction, “Woh! A lot has changed this year!” Things change, people change, plans change, and experience change. One thing stays the same, though, which is our desire to make an impact to our next generations! 😝 Big thanks to everyone who has been part of this journey!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/kevon/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Kevon Cheung&lt;/a&gt; (@kevon) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-10-12T01:11:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 11, 2017 at 6:11pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An annual review cannot be done without a list of books. I didn’t manage to read a lot this year (compared to 26 books in 2016), but a couple books really stood out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37SuxJd&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The E-Myth Revisited: Why Most Small Businesses Don’t Work and What to Do About It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JUe8vJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Extreme Ownership: How U.S. Navy SEALs Lead and Win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JXhRbM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Principles: Life and Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2IDHYUJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3m87SNV&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Monk and the Riddle: The Art of Creating a Life While Making a Living&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3oIESy8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Behind Closed Doors: Secrets of Great Management (Pragmatic Programmers)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;myself&quot;&gt;Myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can feel a huge change in me this year. Long story short, it is a feeling of giving extra care to the people around me, listening first before I speak, and paying attention to things around me. To me, this is a feeling of empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my all-time favorite book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2LqzKQS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life Is What You Make It: Find Your Own Path to Fulfillment&lt;/a&gt;. I love it so much that I give it away as gifts and keep buying physical copies to keep at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BV_K6G9BwFy/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;8&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BV_K6G9BwFy/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;You have to always remind yourself, life is what you make it. Remember, you&amp;#39;re the master of your fate, you&amp;#39;re the captain of your soul.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/kevon/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Kevon Cheung&lt;/a&gt; (@kevon) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-07-01T02:22:59+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 30, 2017 at 7:22pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-could-do-better&quot;&gt;What I Could Do Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In a startup environment, there are a lot to do and sometimes responsibilities are not clear. A few times I found myself being distracted from my core responsibilities. I hope that I could catch myself in time and get back on track.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;People who know me know that I'm introverted. I'm a believer in doing rather than meeting people and talking. While I'm thankful that I have a few friends who I could reach out to talk about achivements and challenges, it is time to branch out to meet more like-minded people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/2017-year-in-review</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/2017-year-in-review</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-12-26T10:54:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>3 Workplace Tips that You Don’t Learn in College</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As people seek more control over their own lives, we hear millennials complain about work all the time. Literally every few days you see or read something along that line. The reasons are, to highlight a few, 1) work is boring, 2) I don’t learn anything, 3) hours are too long and inflexible. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37SuxJd&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The E-Myth Revisited: Why Most Small Businesses Don’t Work and What to Do About It&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Gerber, he said “The work we do is a reflection of who we are. If we’re sloppy at it, it’s because we’re sloppy inside ……. How we do our work becomes a mirror of how we are inside.” So, in the spirit of this, what are somethings that you need to know at workplace yet they don’t teach you in college?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think most young people don’t get that we’re all in control of our lives, which means no one is expected to help you other than yourself. Maybe because work is so different from school. In school, you’re spoon-fed with information and knowledge. At work, you take the driver’s seat to do your own work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-dont-learn-in-college&quot;&gt;What You Don’t Learn in College&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;carry-the-water&quot;&gt;1. Carry the Water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/seekingwisdom&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Seeking Wisdom&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome podcast I’ve been listening to, where I first heard about the concept “Carry the Water” from David and Dave. In school, you only care about your own grade. You might think that to be successful at work, it means a job well done in your own responsibilities. You’re wrong! Because that is not enough. You, as an employee of a company, also need to make your managers successful. “Their lives need to be easier because they hire you.” Dave said. That makes a lot of sense, doesn’t it? Why should they hire you if you need handholding all the time, cannot work independently, and constantly complain? They might be better off without you sucking up their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;am-6pm-work-life-balance-bullshit&quot;&gt;2. 9am-6pm, Work-Life Balance. Bullshit.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In school, we all learn how to meet the minimum requirement and submit the assignment and you could very well be getting A’s. Life is so easy, right? In Rhetoric class, they ask for a 5-page essay, I give them 5 pages. In Finance class, they ask for a financial model, I give them one Excel spreadsheet. At workplace, it is not like that. If you aim for a 9-6 schedule each day, and if you only do what people assign to you, you’re doomed to stay at where you are because you’re not adding extra value, then why do people need to give you more responsibilities and a higher pay? You might think: give me a higher pay and I’ll do more, no, it is the other way around. Nowadays, we like to say “work-life balance” and everyone wants it. I can tell you that it is all bullshit. I can tell you that no good art comes from comfortable artists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-more-update-more&quot;&gt;3. Ask More, Update More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not exactly sure how people worked in the past cause I was not born. I can tell you how work should be like in the present. Let’s talk about school first, you get one big shot for each class, either the final exam or presentation and your grade is based on that. We’re too used to doing things on our own and show it to people only when it is done. The “modern way of working” I say, is work with your manager instead of work for your manager. Ask good questions often, cc her in important emails so she knows what you’re up to, set up 1-on-1 to get feedback. Unless you have a terrible manager, this would be your best way of learning. Do you think that you can learn things naturally? No, you can’t. You learn from books and from people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, in my opinion, school is still an amazing place to be to build your fundamental skills. There are good things you learn there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-do-learn-in-college&quot;&gt;What You Do Learn in College&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-offering-opposing-view-your-habit&quot;&gt;1. Make Offering Opposing View Your Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a small class environment like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.babson.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Babson&lt;/a&gt;, then you get a lot of chance to speak, raise ideas, and discuss with other students (benefit of going to a small school). That’s great because at workplace, you need to keep using your brain juices to come up with new ideas and pitch them. Having ideas is always good, keep them flowing. Opinion is also important. If you’re the type that never has an opposing opinion, then they don’t need you in the meeting. Good managers like opposing views to challenge them. If you think offering opposing view is like a disrespect to your manager, it is either you still don’t get it or you need a better manager who appreciates this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-art-of-speaking-and-rejecting&quot;&gt;2. The Art of Speaking and Rejecting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest thing at workplace is how to reject people nicely. You probably watched the movie “Yes Man”, but don’t be like him; we simply cannot say yes to everything, because not all ideas are great ideas. I think school is a great place to practice that - “Do you want to go to this party tonight?” “Can you let me copy your homework?” “Can you go out with me?” No! No! No! How do you reject people and maintain a good relationship? This is a lifelong learning and good to get some practice in a safe environment like school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, life is what you make it. You define yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/3-workplace-tips-that-you-dont-learn-in-college</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/3-workplace-tips-that-you-dont-learn-in-college</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-02-13T14:08:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>2016 Year in Review</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Always set goals, and always measure them. Here is a list of things I’ve done in the year of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to read 26 books this year, that’s exactly 1 book every 2 weeks. I was hoping I could read more but there were too many things to work on at &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstcodeacademy.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First Code Academy&lt;/a&gt;. My secret is carrying my Kindle everywhere with me when I know I will be waiting, flying, or having no Internet. I did not really have a theme for the year, I would say towards the end of the year, it became more focused on Leadership and Personal Growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W2fpDg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KbQ07N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pour Your Heart Into It: How Starbucks Built a Company One Cup at a Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39ZdlnM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How I Lost 170 Million Dollars: My Time as #30 at Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/377GY4v&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mr. Penumbra’s 24-Hour Bookstore: A Novel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gDSLdS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3oKv5Y6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Lie With Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JSTCeY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bargaining for Advantage: Negotiation Strategies for Reasonable People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3qOMxMW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Delivering Happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3nlI0jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Internet is My Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37Xr7VD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tribal Leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gDdT3X&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I Love You More Than My Dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37cgqzn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shoe Dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3qOMKQe&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Augmented Age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3naWSRf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;High Output Management (yet to finish)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3753ACG&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Building Great Software Engineering Teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3natZ7E&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turn the Ship Around!: A True Story of Turning Followers into Leaders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3qP6tiP&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search Inside Yourself: The Unexpected Path to Achieving Success, Happiness (and World Peace)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W6loXL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mindset (paused)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3a8rXBg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Course of Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39Ze3kW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Do More Faster: TechStars Lessons to Accelerate Your Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Whej77&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Performing Under Pressure: The Science of Doing Your Best When It Matters Most (stopped, not interesting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JJYYcz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peak: How Great Companies Get Their Mojo from Maslow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Lr8qlv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Work Clean: The life-changing power of mise-en-place to organize your life, work, and mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W3NoLH&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Amazon Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W1xz8b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How Google Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3a2hoj9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp;amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;traveling&quot;&gt;Traveling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared with a lot of jetsetters out there, I don’t think the list is even worth sharing. Anyway, I would like to travel more with purpose, say running an oversea half marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Cape Town &amp;amp; Johannesburg, South Africa&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bangkok, Thailand&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bangkok, Thailand&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Rhode Island and Maine, USA&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Phuket, Thailand&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;San Francisco, USA&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Singapore&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Siem Reap, Cambodia&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bali, Indonesia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blogging&quot;&gt;Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including this post, I wrote 5 blog posts this year, far from my initial plan to get 12 blog posts out the door. Definitely something to work on in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/7-books-to-read-in-2016&quot;&gt;7 Books to Read in 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/7-life-mottos-i-live-by&quot;&gt;7 Life Mottos I Live By&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/how-we-define-our-company-culture-at-first-code-academy&quot;&gt;How We Define Our Company Culture at First Code Academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/you-have-been-finding-jobs-the-wrong-way&quot;&gt;You Have Been Finding Jobs The Wrong Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017-year-in-review&quot;&gt;2016 Year in Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-speaking&quot;&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set myself a goal to take on a challenge of speaking in the public this year. It just so happened that WHub was hosting an event about “working at startup” and they invited me to be a panelist. It was my first ever public speaking gig and I was excited to share my startup experience with the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;running&quot;&gt;Running&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my 1st half marathon in 2014 in Singapore, I told myself that the next one would not be coming soon. 2 years later, I figured I needed some new challenges in my life, and so instead of joining another half marathon, I joined 2. With a training plan in mind, I ran regularly throughout the year and achieved a personal best of 2h4m at Angkor Wat Half Marathon, 4m behind my target yet still a major improvement. I’m thinking to sign up more half marathons in 2017, anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;HKDRC Half Marathon - 2016 Oct&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Angkor Wat Half Marathon - 2016 Dec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/2016-year-in-review</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/2016-year-in-review</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-12-20T21:51:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>You Have Been Finding Jobs The Wrong Way</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you were just on any job portal like JobsDB or LinkedIn looking for a job, you might want to read this blog post because you have been finding jobs the wrong way. Everyone knows that finding a job is hard, almost as hard as finding your significant half. What’s worse is, when you start dating someone you don’t like that much, which is kind of like taking a job you’re not so interested in. Now, if you want to find a job that you actually enjoy, read on. Disclaimer: this is more for a startup job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-rely-on-jobs-portal&quot;&gt;Don’t Rely on Jobs Portal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a company puts up a job opening on a job portal, it is because it is the fastest way to source a large pool of applicants. They have an opening and you want a job, doesn’t that sound like the perfect match? The truth is, how do you know that you are actually interested in the company, the role, and the people, or you are simply just getting a job for the sake of having a job? It is possible that you will end up with something you are happy with through job portals, but to maximize your chance of finding a job you desire , you must do things differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Company&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read a lot about what people out there are doing and know what gets you curious. For example, if you read an article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstcodeacademy.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First Code Academy&lt;/a&gt; on Tech in Asia, go to First Code’s website, and if what they do get your attention, go to the Career page and start looking around for a role that you have the skills and passion for. Apply there. If you want to go the extra mile, find out the person who is in charge of hiring and impress them, possibly the founder(s) or founding member(s). In the past at First Code, we have received from these applicants market research, new campaign ideas for marketing, or even illustration on why they would be a good fit to us. Try not to go to the Human Resources person as they have seen too many applicants and all they do is filtering based on a few criteria to lower your chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Read more news about what companies are out there doing cool things, approach the cool companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you surf the internet, every time you stumble upon people who are inspiring to you and you dream of working alongside them, take down their names and where they work. Getting to know them would be a challenge as you can expect that a lot of others are doing the same to approach them. Yet people say “If there is a will, there is a way”, dig around the internet until you can find the contact. Write a personalized email and try creative ways to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Working in a startup means working closely with the founders. If the founder is inspiring and can teach you loads, that’s the startup you want to work in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-out&quot;&gt;Go Out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since cold emailing people is difficult, your best bet is to be out there and constantly meet people and make friends. You don’t need an intention to make friends, but you never know when you would bump into someone who is doing really cool, amazing things. People call this “networking”, and yes, there is no secret sauce to it. I met Michelle, founder of First Code Academy, at a Sunday Entrepreneur meetup one day in 2013, and we only started a conversation about working together at the end of 2014. See?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Branch out and meet more people. A lot of them are doing cool things, you might not get a job right away, but opportunities might show up in front of you one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a job you desire is extremely important. Think about it - when you do not have a job you enjoy, you start looking around for another job. After a few switches, commitment becomes the first thing any interviewer asks you and it hurts your chance of getting a job. Therefore, to find a job that you are excited about has a long-term effect on your career, and just remember one thing, everything builds on top of each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/you-have-been-finding-jobs-the-wrong-way</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/you-have-been-finding-jobs-the-wrong-way</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-09-09T21:49:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>How We Define Our Company Culture at First Code Academy</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since Michelle and I read Tony Hsieh’s Delivering Happiness, we were intrigued by the way Tony runs Zappos and how culture plays a major role in the building of the shoe empire. Nowadays, a respectable company is not represented by its huge revenue or operating margin, a more convincing way of measuring is through its impact on the world and its employee’s happiness. In the book, Tony mentioned that there are only 3 key areas that are worth investing into when everything else could be copied easily, and the trio is a brand, culture, and pipeline. With a huge admiration towards building a well-defined company culture, I want to talk about how we define our culture at &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstcodeacademy.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First Code Academy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I joined First Code in January 2015, it was the early period of the startup (one and a half year in). The campus looked like someone just rented an empty furnished space yesterday, the people have titles but no one was exactly sure what to work on, and there was certainly no sign of a strong culture. Just like most startups, at that point of time, the style (I wouldn’t say culture) of First Code was hugely defined by the personality of its founder, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sunmichelle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Michelle&lt;/a&gt;. It was about working hard, moving fast, experimenting new ideas, and becoming close to our parents and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We focused most of our energy on making sure the startup was growing rapidly and we were achieving goals that we set for ourselves. What we neglected was the development of a place where people would wake up and be excited about it, would stay after working hours just because they genuinely want to, and would talk about it casually with anyone like it is her own business. It was until late 2015 that Michelle and I started to think about what a company culture meant and really poured our heart into shaping a culture at First Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started reading a lot of books about this topic, Tony Hsieh’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3qOMxMW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Delivering Happiness&lt;/a&gt;, Howard Schultz’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KbQ07N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pour Your Heart Into It: How Starbucks Built a Company One Cup at a Time&lt;/a&gt;, and Phil Knight’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37cgqzn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shoe Dog&lt;/a&gt; were the prints that really got a piece of our hearts. We jotted down notes while reading them, and instantly they sparked interesting things we wanted to try at First Code. We understood that culture couldn’t be developed in a day or by one person, and evidently, it was not shaped solely by executing a few todos. It was going to take time and determination, and we had both. The next step was to put them into actions, finding out what culture and values our team possessed by digging into our memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/firstcode-teamhk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First Code Academy Team Hong Kong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be easier to list out 8-10 core values to First Code and then ask every team member to follow, but we chose to do it the other way around - we looked at what examples we could spot in the last few months and we started from there. For example, First Code has been running in a super lean way, and we tend to move into new campus before it is ready. This was a great example of “Done is Better than Perfect”. We often host lunch and learn sessions for team members to share knowledge, be it time management or Photoshop. That’s right, we have “a culture of learning”! When I open my email inbox, I often see tons of emails with replies filled with “Thank you” to our team members for big and small achievements. We “show appreciation and gratitude towards each other on the team”. The list just kept on going until we had to stop and weighed which one was more important as a company. Eventually, with all the examples, we came down to 8 core values at First Code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Done is better than perfect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultivate a culture of learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be resourceful and solution oriented&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be humble&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show appreciation and gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create fun and a bit of spontaneity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a passionate and positive team and family spirit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create impact through community service &amp;amp; social responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These core values and the stories behind them became training materials for each new team member. We do not expect everyone to get it just because we talk about it once, as a matter of fact, the new member has to feel the culture and sees examples in her own eyes. From the day when we wrote down the 8 core values of First Code, we have seen a tremendous increase in actions and behaviors that fit into our culture and values. The team became more efficient as team members started using these core values to make independent decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/firstcode-outing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First Code Academy Team Outing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, though, when you’re inside a bubble, it prevents you from seeing what is outside. Although we were excited and contented about how First Code’s culture was shaping internally, there was one thing we weren’t 100% sure of and we were curious to find out - what would parents say about First Code’s culture? What do they really think? We reached out to a few parents with one simple question “What do you think of First Code Academy’s culture?” The responses were overwhelming and we got a ton of encouragement we did not expect. I would like to share one of the responses that made our hearts drop while reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;“The way that I have experienced First Code culture is by observing the way my daughter &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_ experiences it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First Code is the smartest and most progressive amongst all her activities: art, language, sports on top of her normal international school curriculum. She is truly excited about coming to First Code and especially proud of what she is creating. This is not a “course” to her. It is an expression of herself and a most powerful one as she gains “control” of an environment that she creates. I’d love to be a child again so I could be part of it in that way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As a professional admiring the same people you admire, I see your culture as fun empowering bold and unafraid; approachable collaborative warm yet cool and hip; transparent open forward-looking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Inspired by the ones who made history by thinking further than current reality and inspiring because these heroes are “on the walls” and talking to all of us in your space all the time. As I can compare to P&amp;amp;G, Coca-Cola, COFCO, Swire or &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;__ that I have experienced, another major trait comes up: FRESH, spontaneous, authentic.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
By a Parent of First Code Academy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attribute this positive culture we have to all current and former team members, our parents, and our students. With the energy, excitement, and curiosity from everyone, I believe we are creating a place that is filled with two important elements in life: learning and happiness. So now, for anyone who is running a startup, instead of pulling your hair out to crank out that list of core values, follow the 4 steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn from other companies you admire and take note of their key culture and values&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be a leader and do it yourself; if you do it long enough, your team members will follow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look around and spot examples among the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a list of company core values, make them part of the required training materials, and continue to iterate on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is one example of your team that clearly defines your company culture? Drop me a note. Would like to hear it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested to read more about First Code’s culture: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hk.firstcodeacademy.com/careers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;firstcodeacademy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/how-we-define-our-company-culture-at-first-code-academy</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/how-we-define-our-company-culture-at-first-code-academy</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-08-28T21:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>7 Life Mottos I Live By</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many life mottos out there from all these famous people; for me, I believe everyone should have a personal set of life mottos and it is worth writing them down so we can remind ourselves from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From reflecting my early career, these are the 7 ones that shape me into who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you can’t do the small things well, don’t mind the big things&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Never be late&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be humble, there are a lot of people smarter than you&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Early birds get the worms&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you cannot decide for yourself, no one can&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t look back, look forward&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hard work will pay off, just be patient&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/7-life-mottos-i-live-by</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/7-life-mottos-i-live-by</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-05-02T21:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>7 Books to Read in 2016</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Year 2016 is the first year I am drafting up a detailed annual plan for myself. After reading Chris Guillebeau’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisguillebeau.com/how-to-conduct-your-own-annual-review/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“How to Conduct Your Own Annual Review”&lt;/a&gt;, I came up with 14 measureable targets in the fields of Relationship (Family &amp;amp; Friends), Finance, Health, Learning, and Travel. I didn’t set a target for reading books because it is a no brainer for me that I must and will read a lot. It is funny because I hated reading in my childhood, and now I treat books as one of my closest friends, so I spent some time making a list of books I will read in 2016. I hope you’ll find some of them interesting, and please also share with me what you’re reading!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-thing-explainer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/379Jjw1&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto379jjw1-targetblankthing-explainer-complicated-stuff-in-simple-wordsa&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/379Jjw1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thing Explainer: Complicated Stuff in Simple Words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Randall Munroe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; Heard that the author only uses the 1,000 most common words in the English language to explain various subjects. Perfect for someone like me who doesn’t have a large library of vocabularies but still have the curiosity to explore new topics!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Review on Mar 20, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; It is not as interesting as it seems. The words end up being too simple to actually tell you anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-mindset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W6loXL&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto2w6loxl-targetblankmindset-the-new-psychology-of-successa&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W6loXL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mindset: The New Psychology of Success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Carol Dweck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; From my last blog post, I talked about success, and I do believe mindset is one of the keys to success.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Review on Jan 27, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; Hmmm, I would not recommend this book at all, I stopped reading because of 2 main reasons.
&lt;br /&gt;
1) After reading around different chapters, it seems to only talk about one message - why you should have a growth mindset, not a fixed mindset. Using a lot of small stories to bring out the same message, the book does feel like an infinite loop.
&lt;br /&gt;
2) And the stories are not even interesting ……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-superbosses.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W6mD9n&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto2w6md9n-targetblanksuperbosses-how-exceptional-leaders-master-the-flow-of-talenta&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W6mD9n&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Superbosses: How Exceptional Leaders Master the Flow of Talent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Sydney Finkelstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; A new book without any review yet, but leadership book is always a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-sprint.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/375OaOA&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto375oaoa-targetblanksprint-how-to-solve-big-problems-and-test-new-ideas-in-just-five-daysa&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/375OaOA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sprint: How to Solve Big Problems and Test New Ideas in Just Five Days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Jake Knapp, John Zeratsky, Braden Kowitz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; Sprint is a popular concept in the startup space yet no one really knows how it works; I’m curious to find out more about how to build products faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-nonsense.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3a0rEbH&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto3a0rebh-targetblanknonsense-the-power-of-not-knowinga&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3a0rEbH&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nonsense: The Power of Not Knowing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Jamie Holmes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; I’m quite intrigued by the ambiguity of many things, maybe it is better staying this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-perform-under-pressure.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gzxvGr&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto3gzxvgr-targetblankperforming-under-pressure-the-science-of-doing-your-best-when-it-matters-mosta&quot;&gt;6. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gzxvGr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Performing Under Pressure: The Science of Doing Your Best When It Matters Most&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Hendrie Weisinger, J. P. Pawliw-Fry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; Some people say they cannot deal with pressure, yet some people like Cristiano Ronaldo (famous footballer) said he loves the pressure of the game. I just want to do my best.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Review on Mar 20, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; Again, not a big fan of theory book in which what the author does is just simply bring out examples after examples to prove a simple point. It doesn’t excite me at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/book-when-breathe-becomes-air.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;img-source&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3qOlodl&quot; taret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hrefhttpsamznto3qolodl-targetblankwhen-breath-becomes-aira&quot;&gt;7. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3qOlodl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Paul Kalanithi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; A close one of mine passed away from lung cancer 16 years ago. What does it feel like when you’re so close to death? I want to find out.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Review on Feb 10, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; A strong recommendation. I don’t think a lot of people actually study death before it hits them, which is sad because a lot of times it could be too late. I like the book a lot because it carries us through his own life, the gains, and the struggles… it is very real, too real. You could feel the author’s perseverance in fighting for his life.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/7-books-to-read-in-2016</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/7-books-to-read-in-2016</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-01-16T22:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Knowing Yourself is The Key to Your Own Journey</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One night over dinner, a college friend asked me “What is your life goal?” It was definitely a rare question that not many peers have asked me at this stage of our lives. It was a tough question! I don’t know what life goals I have because it changes all the time. If you asked me in primary school, I would have given you the standard “a businessman” answer. In high school, you might hear “an investment banker who makes a lot of money”. And then in college, you probably hear “an aspiring figure who stands out from the crowd”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night, my answer was “I wanted to be successful, of course it is based on your own definition of success, then I want to enjoy what I do and keep learning and learning.” To me, I think I know myself pretty well to make the appropriate small steps towards a life I want. I’m not saying I can help you find yourself, nor am I the person you should learn from if you’re lost, I just want to share my thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of times, I hear peers saying that they do not know what they want in life, as they just want to live well. They can’t figure out a key interest that they want their lives to be evolved around. I find it weird, particularly because we as humans should be pretty good at finding out what we like, say we know what food we like, we know what we prefer to do over weekend, and we know which songs we like most. It should be pretty easy to know what we like, is it not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am determined that my career and life will be surrounded by tech, using software to make lives more efficient and fun. I don’t know exactly what it will be, or whether the idea will change, but at least for now, this is what I’m aiming for. So how do I find this out? What is the searching process? One trick is I think about what I did most as a kid. What were you doing most of the time in your childhood? Was it playing violin? Was it creating nice artwork in sketch book? What about on the weekend? Did you spend all night, sacrificing your sleep, to work on something you love? Most of the time, if you’re willing to sacrifice time to do one thing over another, you’re interested in it. This is a good place to start to find your true interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me when I was a 13-14 years old boy, I was playing a bit of sports, but my true passion was going home to sit in front of my computer. I would go online, looked at my favorite websites, checked out what new features or designs they have implemented, and finally copied as much as I could to my very own website. Reverse-engineering and replicating was an excellent way to learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After knowing what you like, it is time to break it down into small steps so it is more achievable. You can’t expect yourself to be one of the crazy millionaire stories out there, instead be humble and come up with a plan. After majoring in Finance in college, I knew that it was not worth my time getting a job in that field, because eventually I would switch because of lack of interest and start from scratch again. I tried running a business with peers when I was at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.babson.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Babson College&lt;/a&gt;, where we had this FME course and everyone had to be part of a business. To be honest, that was good but it wasn’t real! To get the real failure, the only way is to try it. Therefore, I told myself, why not try and fail and see what I’m good at and what I’m bad at. I worked on a startup idea for 6 months. Ended up, I wasn’t good at anything and I have dozens of things to improve on. So, tackle one baby step, one goal at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I’m sharing how to find myself, I’m still far, really far away from success. I set high bars for myself in order to achieve more in life and I believe I can make it one day, just not sure when. From all the things I’m bad at, I cherry picked coding to be my next focus. Why? Because I spent a lot of time working on websites and I got a lot of satisfaction from it. So it is time to learn how to code. Making websites did not count as coding to me back then, because there were lots of tools that helped you. All you need to do is read the installation guide and work your way out. To code means creating the whole structure of a website, understanding data models, and processing information from one end to another. How I learn to code was a long process. I won’t get into it today, but it was this small desire of knowing how to code that I studied coding for 9 months and eventually landed a job as a Software Engineer to face the world with a new skill I just acquired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if I haven’t gone far enough from where I started, in about a year time, I realized business skills were essential no matter what industry you’re in. When I worked as a programmer, I observed how my boss and managers deal with clients and was immediately curious to find out what it means to run and deal with real people. When I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://firstcodeacademy.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First Code Academy&lt;/a&gt; from Michelle, the founder, I could see myself being part of it because it combines startup, education, and technology. It seemed like a perfect fit to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking you through the 3 changes in my life is because I want to tell you that, to be joyful waking up everyday, first you need to know what you want (something small and achievable). Based on that, you will find a job that doesn’t feel like a job, as you enjoy what you do and pour your heart into it (Read Howard Schultz’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KbQ07N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pour Your Heart Into It: How Starbucks Built a Company One Cup at a Time&lt;/a&gt; - True Story of Starbucks). Everyday serves as a lesson; ask humble questions and seek advice from people who have done it already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister once told me that everyone on earth gets 24 hours a day, in which 8 hours are spent in sleep, another 8 are allocated for work, and the remaining 8 hours are the key that defines a person’s life. Whether I choose to watch TV or read books, go on Youtube or take an online course, or get drunk with friends or chat with friends to push each other forward, these decisions are crucial when the 8 hours accumulate. This cannot be more true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final word, when you wonder what your next job is, just find out one thing you seek to learn (say building your network, or mastering social media marketing, or becoming a rockstar sales) and stop being greedy. There is no perfect job out there, as long as you stay true to yourself, you’ll integrate everything and that would be your “perfect job”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/knowing-yourself-is-the-key-to-your-own-journey</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/knowing-yourself-is-the-key-to-your-own-journey</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-11-24T22:45:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>What a Developer / Software Engineer Should Expect Working in an Agency</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it has been almost a year since I last wrote a blog post. I would like to take this chance to give an update on what I’m doing. Since leaving &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.favoritemedium.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Favorite Medium&lt;/a&gt;, a Software Development Agency in Singapore, at the end of 2014, I joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstcodeacademy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First Code Academy&lt;/a&gt; in Hong Kong with a mission to empower the next generation to become creators with technology. I am taking this chance to reflect on my experience working as a Software Engineer in an agency, hoping that those who are looking for jobs after a coding bootcamp will see this post and find it helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uncertain-time-span-for-each-project&quot;&gt;1. Uncertain time span for each project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on a client project means you’ll have no idea how long you’ll be paired with the product, sometimes it could mean years, or 3 weeks. The benefit of working in an agency is that the project tends to be short, such as 3 months, and you’ll be working on a new project with a different stack. If you’re lucky to be with an agency like Favorite Medium, you’ll be exposed to a lot of projects that are built from scratch, from architecture, to APIs, to Android apps. They will also allow you to build internal projects while waiting for a client project to kick off, and you can learn Angular JS, Scala, or whatever you find interesting! Amazing right? The downside is you will also get projects that last more than a year and so called “Legacy Code” that is hard to maintain after more than a dozen programmers have worked on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-programmer-needs-to-know-how-to-communicate&quot;&gt;2. A programmer needs to know how to communicate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest takeaways from my experience there was how to communicate with your team and external clients. I remembered I was sent to Seoul, Korea to handover a project to our Korean client. The team there was a group of Microsoft programmers, and they did not program in Ruby. My task was to advise them how to set up their own servers, databases, and local development environment. I also had to teach them how to make code changes. It was an extremely difficult thing to do as they only spoke half English. The good thing was that all of them were truly talented and picked up in 4 days and I got to return to Singapore with a smile. Being a programmer is not just about banging out code on your keyboards, you need to know how to document the code, you need to be able to explain what you just did in plain language and defend your decision to code in a certain way, and you need to communicate! Yes, a lot of communication! For me, I would say the best programmers tend to challenge others to do things in better ways, present their ideas concisely and clearly, and share their knowledge with peers. These all make use of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;client-is-king&quot;&gt;3. Client is king&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developer and design team has a ton of expertise in the field and is able to make recommendations on how a project can be built. However, as all of you know, client is king. They have their own priorities and preference in the product, so in many cases, you’ll have to compromise in order to fit their timeline, taste, and everything. It is not exactly different in other industries anyway. Personally I think working with client is something every should master, and you shouldn’t let this scare you away from working at an agency. At the end of the day, if you’re working in a startup, your client is your coworkers. If you’re a founder of a startup, your client is everyone in your company and all your customers. So, practice the art of working with clients!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-code-that-other-programmers-can-understand&quot;&gt;4. Write code that other programmers can understand&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of times, you think that you are the only person who is on this project, and start to go down the messy-code approach. Never do that! You might think that it is just “testing code” and you’ll fix it later to clean it up. The truth is once it is developed, it is hard to redo it (just simply a hassle and I think only a few will do that). Naming variables is the simplest thing in programming, but it is an art. To name your varaibles so that it is short and everyone can understand is hard. I learn the hard way as the senior programmer I worked with often scolded at me for the terrible naming conventions. Besides, document the code well and do it frequently, do not leave it til the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-it-like-working-in-an-agency&quot;&gt;5. What is it like working in an agency?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky, the culture and environment of the agency should facilitate learning. At Favorite Medium, the managers are super open about learning new things, a new language or framework. Projects often have realistic deadlines, and you’ll be learning while working. Of course, there are times where you have to rush something before the deadline, then the team works in the evening as well, but deadline doesn’t happen frequently. Hours are fixed and working environment is relaxed. A lot of the meetings will be hosted online through Google Hangout or Skype, but you won’t really work directly with the client. Usually there is a project manager in between who handles client communication and assign tasks accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-words&quot;&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent learning experience to start off your career at an agency (aka development house), find out what you truly like and go from there. I had an amazing time in the 14 months at Favorite Medium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/what-a-developer-should-expect-working-in-an-agency</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/what-a-developer-should-expect-working-in-an-agency</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-06T19:19:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Why You Should Work Overseas in Your Early Career</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exactly 123 days ago I moved to Singapore, from Hong Kong, and began to live a life I would never have imagined before. No, it is not one of those dramatic, crazy lives you’ve seen in the movies; in fact it is a simple, peaceful life of a 23-year-old continuing to be alone overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that I work away from my home city has given me a chance to look at another concrete jungle in Asia in a local perspective. Most importantly, I have no fear of being alone and am able to form numerous excellent habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the pros of working overseas far exceed the cons in this early stage of my career, hence I would hope that more young people would opt to do the same before it is too late. Responsibilities tend to pile up as you get older, and it is likely you’ll stay in your home city for the rest of your life, then these few years fresh off university might be your favorable time to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-with-your-eyes-not-your-camera&quot;&gt;Travel with your eyes, not your camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word “traveling” has a special meaning to me. Most of the time you and I, the ones that have a full-time job and only have limited days to travel, would fly to a city or island with a “tourist” book in hand that you pick up from the bookstore. You eat, you walk, you snap a few photos, and in no time you’re back at home. I enjoy this kind of exploration, but something is missing from this 5-day-trip, something important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of the fun, I also care and want to know more about what local people do over weekends, how the government is helping its people, and why expats enjoy working in this city etc. I need way more than 5 days to achieve that. Personally, from spending three months in New York in the summer of 2013, to now I’ve been in Singapore for four months, I know for the fact that you have to be physically present in a city to find out the answers to those questions, and trust me, this is way more fulfilling than just being a tourist and eating local food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-your-eyes-in-multiple-aspects&quot;&gt;Open your eyes in multiple aspects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a job in Singapore, and that opened a door for me to learn how I would survive in the two major cities, Hong Kong and Singapore, because I got to evaluate income in relative to cost of living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income is probably the first factor everyone looks at, but living standard is as important. For example, the same job in the two cities might make you the same amount of money, but which one costs you more? Some insights I’ve gathered over the past few months allow me to do simple comparison between Hong Kong and Singapore. In terms of food, Singapore has more choices which you could go from a $4SGD dinner or a $120 one and still get your stomach filled, whereas in Hong Kong, the starting point is slightly higher and you can hardly find a $25HKD dinner. If you can handle hawker food, you will be able to save a ton of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For transportation, Singapore is well connected through MRT and bus, and to go from airport to downtown, it costs you $2SGD if you take MRT! It would take you about $40HKD for bus or $60-100 for airport express if you’re in Hong Kong. Again, big money saver. Lastly, Singapore has a 7% tax on goods and services, so shopping definitely will hurt your wallet. And the list goes on and on, but you get the point. From daily tiny things, you could find out about the city and make comparisons to where you come from. Maybe one day you’ll find a place that fits your lifestyle more than your home town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-uncomfortable-and-grow-to-be-fearless-and-independent&quot;&gt;Be uncomfortable and grow to be fearless and independent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate benefit of working overseas is definitely the personal growth you’ll achieve. In a new city, you have a ton of time with yourself. You’ll have plenty of time to think about your life and how you want to pursue goals. Working in a new city is different from studying in university; those in your age and with similar background are not there anymore, you’re all alone. However, the greatest thing about being alone is you’re so independent that you no longer fear to be alone. You spend your time wisely and appreciate the number of things you’re able to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have formed a number of habits, which include working out regularly, reading books, trying out different activities, and blogging (sharing) of course! I would hit the gym whenever I can; I would read a lot of books I enjoy (I was never a reading person, I have always hated it); I would go rock climbing and archery on the weekends; I would enjoy a Sunday afternoon at home or in a park reading about Hatching Twitter and writing up blog posts. I have no doubt I’ve developed a healthy routine for myself, and I’m enjoying. If I were in Hong Kong, it would have been much more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, since I’m in an entirely fresh place without any best friends around, every single person I meet post a new challenge to me. I have to figure out the best way to interact with them, and this teaches me about people! Sometimes I have to get out of my comfort zone, but that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, above are just the obvious reasons for working overseas, there are much more to the experience. I hope I have given you enough reasons to at least think about your young career or even make an attempt to apply for a job elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/why-you-should-work-overseas-in-your-early-career</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/why-you-should-work-overseas-in-your-early-career</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-03-06T16:16:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>10 Lessons I Learned From My First Failed Startup</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing up this post has been in my mind since about a year ago in the beginning of 2013. That was the time when I decided Sponfed would not work out and it was time for us to move on. The delay came from my busy schedule to picking up coding and finding a software engineer job. I wrote half of it in late-2013, but never managed to finalize the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flashing back to the summer of 2012, I graduated from college and had to face the crude real world. Only in my senior year had I discovered more about tech, web development, and startups, so I had been brainstorming for ideas throughout my final year in college. After two months of preparation, Sponfed was launched in September 2012 as a sponsorship platform startup to connect brand owners and event organizers. The idea was exciting, and everyone I met loved it. Most of them even expressed strong need in this service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next six months was a big learning curve for me and my two co-founders. There were tons of meetings, tons of networking events, some pitches, and some rough work developing the website. In March 2013, I decided to accept that we failed to turn the (we thought) brilliant idea into a business, and called a peaceful breakup. We went separate ways and continued on the journey each person had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing startup is tough, and that’s why everyone should try it. Only if you have tried to take on the challenge would you understand the magic and challenge inside. Here I want to share 10 lessons I learned from this particular failure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;age-matters-and-be-in-the-right-industry&quot;&gt;1. Age matters and be in the right industry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a startup to sell a product, taking even $10 from a customer is hard enough. Sponfed intended to connect sponsorships that were range from $3,000HKD to $1,000,000HKD, this kind of deals wasn’t something three twenty-something years old could easily do. People tend to associate your age with your ability to do business in that price range. In your 20s, it is much more convincing to work on creative ideas that do not have a huge price tag. Be at the right place at the right time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-be-afraid-to-share-equity-idea-and-success&quot;&gt;2. Don’t be afraid to share equity, idea, and success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the preparation period, I was out seeking for technical co-founder or a team of developers to work together to build this sponsorship platform. I had a few great choices, from freelancer, to web dev firm, to unknown tech guy who seemed to have more than 10 years of experience in building successful online businesses, but I was too worried about the potential consequences to get these people on board. What if they screw me over? What if the tech guy has absolute control over the company because he handles all the code (the valuables). You can’t be scared of every tiny detail. If you pick the right person, the business will go a step further; if you do not pick at all, you’re still at step zero. However, keep in mind that at the end of the day, if you don’t know your co-founder well or you have never worked with him/her before, it will be a huge challenge going forward in months, or years. To start the first venture, never plan to do everything by yourself, pick the right talent and build it together.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iterate-and-learn&quot;&gt;3. Iterate and learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building startup is like standing in a forest, you never know what is in front of you and which direction leads to the way out. The key is make a ton of assumptions, test and validate them, and constantly look for feedback from real customers. To sum it up, just follow Lean Startup. Our team did not learn and iterate fast enough; it was also because of the lag time between each communication point. I recommend setting up morning meeting to reflect and go over lessons learned from the previous day and try to adjust the startup’s direction quickly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-meet-everyone&quot;&gt;4. Don’t meet everyone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a business, people love to meet up with you to have coffee to explore opportunities. However, in early stage, only meet with the ones that are potential customers or could offer significant advice. This is because meeting people is extremely time consuming and most of the time, you gain nothing. In Sponfed, we had to meet up with a lot of brand owners and event organizers to learn about their needs, only about 30% of the meetings actually carry on and turn into further discussion. Make your selection wise.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build-a-team-with-different-talents&quot;&gt;5. Build a team with different talents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three co-founders of Sponfed were all non-technical (and now I’m a Software Engineer). I was the one who took care of the website, one of them was doing marketing and PR, and another was on sales and operation. It seems like a good combination of people, yet don’t forget we were planning to be in the tech scene. Therefore, instead of three business people, a more ideal combo would be a developer, a designer, and a business person. Make sure your team has different skill-sets when you start.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-takes-time-so-have-faith&quot;&gt;6. It takes time, so have faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took Sponfed a couple months to build partnerships with other companies and got actively approached by event organizers. Almost 99% of startups don’t get the attention they want, and what you should do is have faith in your business if it works, and one day it will come back to you. Keep fighting until you reach a point where things cannot be changed. If you’re dead sure about that, then call a breakup and try again in the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-prototype-needs-to-work&quot;&gt;7. A prototype needs to work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we didn’t get a developer in our team, I was the one who built the website for Sponfed and it did not have a lot of functions. Bounce rate was almost 70% and retention rate was 0%, basically after the first visit, no one would come back to our website. Our prototype was more or less a website showcasing the business, thus there was no purpose for them to come back after the first time. To create a platform, make sure the prototype has enough functionalities to get going. Don’t just tell what you do, show what you can do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;people-are-generally-nice&quot;&gt;8. People are generally nice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go out and tell people about your idea, I would say about 80% of the time, you would receive feedback that praises the idea. They would say they would use your service if they’re an event organizer. Don’t get tricked into this illusion and think that your idea or business can make big money now, the reality is feedback is easy to give, money is not. Instead of telling people about your idea, I would recommend going straight to the customer and see if they would pay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freemium-is-dangerous&quot;&gt;9. Freemium is dangerous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pricing strategy called Freemium has become significantly popular in the last few years. The idea is to give customers a taste of your service so that they’ll be willing to pay to use more features. Be careful of this strategy because in order to move from free to a payment, it takes extra effort to show the value you’re bringing to the table. At Sponfed, we were offering our service for free to begin with, and we even offered extra manual help to ensure everything went our way. It was a dangerous move as we moved from an online service to an offline service, and we were not validating the right assumption. So, it makes sense to offer a free account type if you’re building a software, if not, you are better off charging people on the first day and really validate your assumption.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;say-thank-you-to-families-and-friends&quot;&gt;10. Say thank you to families and friends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without their support, doing startup will be a rougher and tougher path. It takes a ton of courage to be in this space, it takes a ton of braincells to be thinking about how to work it out all day, and it takes up a ton of opportunity cost. Nevertheless, the experience is unforgettable and the realization will only bring you more greatness in the future, regardless of what you do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for reading this, I hope you will make the same mistake that I made, but realised them faster, as only mistakes will make you stronger. Stay cool and carry on!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/10-lessons-i-learned-from-my-first-failed-startup</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/10-lessons-i-learned-from-my-first-failed-startup</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-02-06T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>First Job as a Software Engineer in Singapore</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So it was almost two months since my last blog post, and it wasn’t because I was not keeping up with my tech learnings. It was more because I was busy looking for a company I see fit and going through the interview process. Now that I’ve settled down in Singapore, I can review my process of landing a job with you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I graduated with GA WDI in the first week of September, I had a few days off visiting friends in Austin, Texas (first time, good memories) and then headed back to Hong Kong to begin my job search. There are about three types of companies that I could look into: 1) startups with fresh idea and team, 2) software development agencies, and 3) enormous advertising agencies with media work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of them posts a different pros and cons list, and there isn’t a way to measure them without working in every single one. Thus, I went with my gut feelings, but first let me briefly run through what each of them is like. Startups (3-5 people team) are a tough land for Junior Developers, they tend to look for developers that are generalists with more experience. Even when the startups get up to 50 people, with a 7-8 people dev team, they’re still very reluctant in hiring a junior guy who requires lots of attention. Dev shops or agencies are in high demands, they usually receive a lot of projects, ranging from large big-name clients to small startup websites, thus they’re more willing to hire developers in different levels. The pros about dev shop are you will be in a high-pressure env with tight deadlines, forcing you to work smartly and to pick up new materials quickly, the con is that the deadlines discourage you to learn new exciting things you want to. Lastly, huge ad agencies, they definitely have the tightest deadline in all because they serve big-names. Most of their works are about creative and media, so it could be a touchscreen product for guests to play with at an opening event, or a digital directory placed in the mall. It will be an exciting place to work in if you’re into front-end and media work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah..I have a hard time choosing how to start my career as a Software Engineer. I ended up joining a software development shop called Favorite Medium (FM) with offices in San Fran, Seoul and Singapore (where I’m based now). A huge part of my decision was because of the diverse team FM has, the internatinal coverage, the fact that I’m directly chatting with the CEO since the very beginning, the confidence I have that I’ll be an important part of the company etc. Well, that means cultural and personal fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was exactly a month after I started, and I have been working on a project from front-end, back-end, to deployment. I have to handle everything myself, which is extremely stressful because I haven’t learned a lot of them! But wait, my goal right now is learn and practice, so afterall it is for my own good. From a ruby framework that’s not Rails or Sinatra (rare right?), to JavaScript animations, to API integrations, to AWS deployment… I really picked up a lot from doing this project, I’m also very thankful to have some helpful colleagues who constantly clear off my roadblocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my story for the past two months, it was stressful(!), especially this is my first job and I have to move to a new country. Nevertheless, I’m thankful that my tech journey has kept going strong. If you’re a person currently in a Web Development Bootcamp, feel free to share your story of job searching as well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/first-job-as-a-software-engineer-in-singapore</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/first-job-as-a-software-engineer-in-singapore</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-12-01T15:59:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Hack: How to Use Gmail with Custom Domain for Free</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;When I checked Google Apps for Business last week, I found out that to set up your custom domain to use Gmail, you would have to pay 5 USD per month per user. It was no longer free! A year ago, I was using it for my startup and I remembered it could host up to 10 users for free. To figure out a way so that I can continue using Gmail for my own domain for free, I set out to hack it. And this is how I do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1&quot;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, to start off, you will need to register your own domain name. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.namecheap.com/?aff=57162&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; because it is easy and it covers a lot of extensions, including my new favorite .us (which is only 3 USD per year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2&quot;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting your domain, let’s say yourcustomdomain.com here. You have to login into your Namecheap account and set the DNS to point to your own hosting server. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://secure.hostgator.com/~affiliat/cgi-bin/affiliates/clickthru.cgi?id=bunkev&quot;&gt;Hostgator&lt;/a&gt; for years already because of its great customer service. I usually go on to their online chat and get my question answered within 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3&quot;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you need to register a new Gmail account to connect with your email from custom domain. This will be the account you access everyday. I created kevonishappy@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4&quot;&gt;Step 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head back to Hostgator, log in to the control panel. Create new email account kevon@yourcustomdomain.com and set up email forwarder so that kevon@yourcustomdomain.com will forward all of its email to kevonishappy@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20131013-gmail-01.jpg&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5&quot;&gt;Step 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really this is the last step, log into your Gmail account kevonishappy@gmail.com, and do &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;. Under &lt;strong&gt;Send mail as:&lt;/strong&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;Add another email address you own&lt;/strong&gt;. A pop up window should come up and ask for more information, now enter your name (Kevon) and email address (kevon@yourcustomdomain.com). Leave the &lt;strong&gt;Treat as an alias&lt;/strong&gt; checked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step you would want to choose &lt;strong&gt;Send through yourcustomdomain.com SMTP servers&lt;/strong&gt;. For SMTP Server: enter mail.yourcustomdomain.com. For Username and Password, enter your credentials for your kevon@yourcustomdomain.com. After that, simply go to your webmail, which is yourcustomdomain.com/webmail, and log in to verify the connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20131013-gmail-02.jpg&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-words&quot;&gt;Final Words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now not only you receive all your emails from kevon@yourcustomdomain.com in your kevonishappy@gmail.com account, you can also send or reply email as kevon@yourcustomdomain.com! How amazing and cost-effective is that for a startup company? I hope this helps out anyone who has this trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/hack-how-to-use-gmail-with-custom-domain-for-free</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/hack-how-to-use-gmail-with-custom-domain-for-free</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-10-13T11:46:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Project Kick with Data Visualization</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I’m exposed to two projects built by WDI alumni Larry Buchanan, I was determined to have a second project based on Data Visualization. What it means is extracting an enormous lot of data from somewhere, analyze them, and display the data in a way that an everyday person could understand. Great, the next step, the most difficult indeed, was to find the data. My partner Alina and I started out looking for datasets everywhere, and it was not an easy task. The data has to be formatted in a not-so-ugly way, and it has to be somewhat interesting. We began our project by researching on how to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://datamine.mta.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New York MTA API&lt;/a&gt;, but the General Transit Feed Specification (GTFS) was a little too much to take on at that moment, so we set out to work on another very exciting idea about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kickstarter.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kickstarter only has a private API, whereas other crowd funding site like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdtilt.com/learn/developers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Crowdtilt&lt;/a&gt; offers a public API. However, we were only interested in the crowd funding giant and would not give up just because they don’t have an API. Scraping immediately came to our mind, and I literally spent the whole weekend writing up a quite-heavy rake task to scrape Kickstarter.com with Mechanize. The scraping part was not difficult, as Kickstarter provides metadata that is very recognizable DOM elements to Mechanize. The tough part was figuring out the actual URL i should tell Mechanize to do the job, as Kickstarter uses AJAX request to pull in data when a user scroll down, so HTML only displays the first 15 projects, not the ones that come in by AJAX. Here’s the trick, simple as it seems, pagination is a must have on many websites, so I simply placed a page number at the end of the url and all the pages are in front of my eyes immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After scraping, another major task of ours was to analyze and display the data. We had spent more time working with D3 to display the data as it was our first time playing with it, thus we need to learn from scratch in a very short period of time. Therefore, our data analysis part was not very extensive but that’s a way to improve in the future. Working with D3 was harder than I thought, not only do I need a good Javascript foundation, but it was a nice (weird) concept to learn. The way D3 works is that you have to select elements that are not there yet, by doing so, you’re telling the program “Hey, my friends are not here yet, but let me reserve some seats for them!” A few articles about D3 that really got me off the ground are listed at the end of this blog post. I strongly recommend spending some time reading about D3, looking at what other developers did with it, and then play with it by creating simple rectangles and circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the two main components of Project Kick (&lt;a href=&quot;http://projectkick.us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;projectkick.us&lt;/a&gt;), and now is lesson time! After we had our rake task to scrape the entire Kickstarter site, we had a database filled with raw data, and they are not directly useful to D3 because it is best for D3 when the entire dataset is formatted nicely. The challenge we faced was turning the raw data into an useful set of data specifically for D3, and so we had to write another rake task to populate extra tables for formatted data. My recommendation on that is to do it the other way around, figured out what data is needed in D3’s standpoint, and extract data based on that. Of course, we only had a week of time to actually learn so many new things, so we wouldn’t be able to accomplish that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the code now, there are a ton of rooms for improvement. Nevertheless, I’m extremely happy and proud of the project given the production time of one week. I’m excited to show this to everyone and even people at Kickstarter! I slowly come to realize that I enjoy front-end work more, and it is a good sign that I’ve figured out! On a side note, my personal website &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevoncheung.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kevoncheung.com&lt;/a&gt; has finally come to life. It is very simple but good enough at this point as version 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;appendices&quot;&gt;Appendices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;larry-buchanans-projects&quot;&gt;Larry Buchanan’s Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/sandbox/business/citi-bike.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.newyorker.com/sandbox/business/citi-bike.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/sandbox/business/ncaa.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.newyorker.com/sandbox/business/ncaa.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;d3&quot;&gt;D3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mbostock.github.io/d3/tutorial/bar-2.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://mbostock.github.io/d3/tutorial/bar-2.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bost.ocks.org/mike/join/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://bost.ocks.org/mike/join/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thecodingtutorials.blogspot.com/2012/07/introduction-to-d3.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://thecodingtutorials.blogspot.com/2012/07/introduction-to-d3.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fascinatedwithsoftware.com/blog/post/2012/09/01/Visualizing-Data-with-D3.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.fascinatedwithsoftware.com/blog/post/2012/09/01/Visualizing-Data-with-D3.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/project-kick-with-data-visualization</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/project-kick-with-data-visualization</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-08-13T08:15:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>First Hackathon Experience</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past 2 days, I’ve experienced my first ever Hackathon through a hardcore 30 hours coding session. The Hackathon, &lt;a href=&quot;http://battlehack.org/new-york/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Battle Hack New York&lt;/a&gt;, was hosted by Paypal and the winner will compete in the World Finals in San Jose. For me and three other WDI coursemates, our mission was not to win any prizes; our goal was to participate, learn, and have fun. It was quite an experience for a junior developer, thereby I would like to share bits of it with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To kick it off on Saturday morning 9AM, everyone, which means developers, designers, and entrepreneurs, arrive and has a chance to pitch his or her idea by recording a short video. Based on the videos, the rest of the crowd would be able to form teams and started hacking right away. The WDI crew decided to work together because we wanted to build a product together through this first experience, and our idea was a parking spot sharing web app that allows anyone to price tag his parking spot for other users. We splitted up the work, Teddy was in charge of hooking up the Google Map API, Wesley was the front-end designer, whereas Zach and I engaged ourselves in applying the Paypal, Twilio, and Sendgrid APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks were allocated, so we started coding right after lunch. The first few hours was painful as the Paypal API was incredibly tough to implement, and we had to make a couple of trips to get assistance from many people, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/YayNickQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; from Sendgrid and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jonmarkgo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jonathan&lt;/a&gt; from Twilio. If you ask me what’s the biggest thing I got out of this hackathon, I would tell you that we got familiar with a ton of APIs (the four above). After exhausting ourselves with tired eyes in the freezing room, the organizing team suddenly rushed into our room and announced that we’ve won the Best Idea Award with the parking spot app! It was unbelievable, shocking, and even overwhelming to learn about that because now, we are responsible to build a great product by tomorrow, as people are watching us! That thought passed through my mind but soon enough I was back to the excitement, celebrating our victory (haha) of winning four quad-copters among ourselves. The filming crew was absolutely fantastic as they came by many times to interview us about our experience, and we loved to share the journey with the rest of the world, with whoever wanting to start diving into software development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy hours always flew fast, and all of a sudden it was past midnight and we did not get a lot of work done. I basically focused on connecting our application with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twilio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twilio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://sendgrid.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sendgrid&lt;/a&gt;. I was pretty grateful that the two APIs were so much easier to implement than the Paypal API. Taking a short break by walking around NYC Alley became a routine and I saw many after many passed out on couches, whereas the luckier ones took spots in the nap center with air mattress. I was crashing by around 4AM and had to take an hour and half to recharge, when I returned at 6AM, that was when we started sprinting towards our finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone was working hard on his own parts, and we practiced a ton of git commands, finally came to realize how hard it is to do collaborative programming. The product slowly came together and we were feeling great about what we were able to build in the past 20 hours or so, considering we were only programming for five weeks. Not to our surprise, our story actually attracted people and the Paypal team was extra friendly to us, the media interviewed our story, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Generally Assembly&lt;/a&gt; actaully tweeted about us. To that point, we already made a pretty huge accomplishment in our part and we were happy to check out other people’s projects and to learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap up my experience, I totally had a ton of fun at the hackathon. Everyone who wants to become a developer should totally participate in hackathons in any way. Even though our product was not quite up to standard, but it was beautiful in our eyes. I also came to realize the requirement of winning this kind of competition is to have high coding abilith. The idea does not matter as much in a hackathon, though it does matter in a startup competition. In a hackathon, the ability to demonstrate skills and to represent the city to join the World Finals was a big part. However, there is no need to get discourged by that because winning is not the major part of the experience. What I’ve learned in that 30 hours far exceeded anything, and not to mention we won quad-copters, raspberry PI, and a couple free tees!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I went home, I passed out around 9PM on Sunday and slept til 8AM the next morning. It was an amazing sleep. I hope this sharing will tempt you enough to participate in the next hackathon near you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/first-hackathon-experience</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/first-hackathon-experience</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-22T19:14:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Why You Should Take An Immersive Coding Course</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is Week 4 Day 5, and I cannot believe one third of the course has gone by so quickly. I’ve gathered a list of technical topics I want to share, but I can’t seem to find the time to write about them because I’m constantly working on my applications. Today I am going to talk about the difference between learning coding at home using online resources versus taking an immersive course with instructors and other students. I feel that a lot of people also have this concern in mind, “Hey, the course is so expensive, is it worth it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I self taught myself how to code a few months before I enroll into WDI at GA, so I took countless codeschool or codeacademy exercises, read about ten books about different topics such as Ruby, Rails, jQuery etc, did a few tutorials, and built a few simple app with Rails. I did not know how much I taught myself until I’m writing this blog post right now. Nevertheless, I still decided to join an immersive course in New York because they provide experience you’ll never get on your own. I constantly ask myself, “Is this the right decision?”, and to be honest, I was asking myself the same question in Week 1 because I have seen or tried writing so much code in the past few months that learning from the basics seem like learning algebra 2 again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we started off the course learning Ruby, then Sinatra, and now Rails with a bunch of small topics in between. I slowly realized I was wrong. Teaching myself really did get me a jump start to start building with the help of Rails and the dozens of gems out there, but I never really truly understand what each line does. Learning from basics got me thinking, even a simple Ruby program or a Rails app without scaffold become good practice for me. Yesterday I was helping another student for about an hour and half with his Rails app, and do you know how I felt? I felt like a ninja because I understand the connection between codes in Model, View, and Controller! I’m able to explain and guide someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning from basics and getting plenty of practice is just one reason why I would recommend taking an immersive course. The other reasons kicked in this week as we had a panel of Rails developer coming in to speak about their experience and career journey, and give legit advice on how to get there. We also had a field trip yesterday to a New York Startup called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howaboutwe.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How About We&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been to the website before and I thought it is a young startup with maybe 10 employees max, and I was truly impressed when I walked in I to room  of about 30 people (thats just half of them). The best part is yet to come, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wearenytech.com/66-aaron-schildkrout-co-founder-and-co-ceo-of-howaboutwe-com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CEO Aaron Schildkrout&lt;/a&gt;, gave us a talk about development process which starts from ideation, to quarterly evaluate new ideas, to how design and development team have sprints to carry out production. I was smiling the whole time simply because I was amazed with all these things, I was fascinated! I’ve always been interested in startup and there is so much knowledge out there I want to learn. I thought to myself, “This is exactly the environment I want to be in, and this is exactly the process and work I love.” Leaving their office with tons of enlightenment, I know I picked the right path that I love, and I know I made a good decision joining an immersive course because it opens up more knowledge to me than sitting in front of my laptop at home every day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/why-you-should-take-an-immersive-coding-course</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/why-you-should-take-an-immersive-coding-course</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-12T07:39:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Chasing Dream in New York City</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Next week will be a new start for my career as I will be traveling to New York City for an intensive 12-week web development program with General Assembly (GA). For me, the program is a lesson, an adventure, and also a step towards my dream. As you’ve probably read in my past posts, I’ve always wanted to be a web developer, building slick, functional, and fun applications for people to play with. I wanted to build sites like Airbnb, Buzzfeed, Says, and RoomReveal, and more importantly, fun projects like 8tracks and Represent.sg. Nothing gives me more pleasure than creating something from scratch and seeing it evolves into a beautifully designed and functional application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, GA also offers the same course in Hong Kong, yet due to unforeseeable reason, the course is postponed to September. I remembered telling Allison, the GA coordinator in Hong Kong, that I would consider traveling 8000 miles to do the course in Boston or New York because I CANNOT WAIT. A lot of people who are interested in the course might take it to pick up a new skill, or because it is the new trend, but for me, I’ve been teaching myself how to code for the past few months, and I cannot procrastinate for another few months but to dive deep into this field right now. I know this is what I love doing and this is where my passion lies, I can see myself doing this as my career. Therefore, I made up my decision to return to the land I love and picked up this new challenge. What I want to achieve from this program is to search for a startup (an idea) I love and be part of it as a junior developer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few months, since I will only be surrounded by my course mates and codes, this blog will serve as my diary to the immersive web development course. I will be taking notes on the overall experience and new things I learn, it will be a heck of an experience living in NYC by myself, sitting in front of my laptop everyday, and stuffing my brain with new knowledge! I cannot wait, seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck to myself!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/chasing-dream-in-new-york-city</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/chasing-dream-in-new-york-city</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-06-05T19:49:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Are You A Non-technical Co-founder?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Julian from Airbnb recently sent me this article &lt;a href=&quot;http://benogle.com/2013/03/25/an-idea-for-non-technical-founders-service-first-business.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;An idea for non-technical co-founders: try a service-first business&lt;/a&gt; written by Ben Ogle, it was one of the best articles I’ve read so far in my startup career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core point Ben stresses is the approach founders usually have when they first have the “awesome” idea in mind: they tend to believe they have to build out the product first, then market and sell. For non-technical founders, who can they rely on? Oh right, finding a technical founder! Pitch the tech guy your “awesome” idea and pray that he will join you to execute it. HAHA, I’ve gone through that process in 2012 and I can tell you that it is tough, real tough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, all the people think they’ve had the best idea in the world! The reality is we all have different interest, thus a technical guy wouldn’t be as interested in your idea as you are. They probably have much more tech-advanced ideas to pursue on their own or are already collecting a nice paycheck every month from a startup or tech company. What makes them leave behind all these just to swim with you in an open sea? Second, even though you get it built, you still have to find customers. It will be such a waste to have a finished product but no one uses it! Tech person definitely would not like that waste of effort. And that’s why we have “Lean Startup” now to avoid that! If you have no idea what Lean Startup is, &lt;a href=&quot;/crushing-customer-development-in-singapore&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;refer back to my previous post&lt;/a&gt;! Third, having an idea worths nothing, you will have a hard time negotiating with your technical partner. If you have a proven business model, you have the bargaining power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, soo… what shall you, a non-technical co-founder, do? Give up starting a business? No. As Ben mentions, it is possible to start a buisness without any tech, build up the distribution and customers and use technology to scale it up, make it convenient as hell that people cannot resist using it, grow it into a popular startup! You’ve got to try launching a business with resources you can find online like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strikingly.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Strikely&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://launchrock.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Launchrock&lt;/a&gt;, or build a simple website describing your services using Wordpress. I know, more and more people are faking it nowadays, making customers too lazy to sign up because they feel like nothing is true; however, if your product or service is “that good”, they will. If it’s not “that good”, maybe it is not a feasible business!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize all this, don’t waste time going out and looking for technical partner, meet one during a casual gathering or networking session. Use your time to start creating value first, then if you have proved yourself, investors and developers will come to you like sharks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/are-you-a-non-technical-co-founder</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/are-you-a-non-technical-co-founder</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-04-27T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Crushing Customer Development in Singapore</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last six days, I traveled to one of the most exciting cities with curiosity and excitement. I used to live there for two whole years when I was two years old, and there wasn’t a tiny bit of memory left in my head. That’s why I was extremely excited to be back to Singapore all by myself, just adventure and exploration in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose for the trip was to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://leanstartupmachine.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lean Startup Machine&lt;/a&gt; (LSM), an intensive weekend workshop which teaches entrepreneurs and innovators how to build disruptive products. As a believer in lean startup, I had read &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/348QTVz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Ries and &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W9lGgB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Running Lean&lt;/a&gt; by Ash Maurya, but book theories are still in the book, I had to grab this opportunity to attend the hands-on workshop to further learn the concepts. I purposely scheduled to arrive two days ahead of the workshop so that I could make good use of the trip to explore the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At LSM, we formed teams to develop fresh business ideas which we would test with real customers on the streets. The emphasis was using a problem-approach, therefore, we didn’t even think about the solution at the first place, all our effort was on “what problems do people have?” They often emphasized, &lt;span style=&quot;color: #3366ff;&quot;&gt;“The worst thing that can happen is building a product that no one wants!”&lt;/span&gt; As we all got excited about new business ideas, we made all these rough assumptions and it was not surprising to see how many of our assumptions were made up because we thought people want something, but they actually did not want it. Thanks to these real customers’ feedback from embarrassing ourselves on Orchard Road, almost all the teams have changed (we called it pivoted) from the original idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned about the right methodology to do startup at LSM, and I kept referring the concept back to my own startup, Sponfed. I realized there were a ton of mistakes we made: didn’t specify a specific market segment where the early adopters are, didn’t test assumptions and pivot enough, and didn’t come up with a way to present our product effectively when meeting with clients. The sponsorship space is definitely a tough market to go into, but we could have been more successful to tackle the problems if we had used the lean startup concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;half&quot; alt=&quot;Clarke Quay&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;half&quot; alt=&quot;Marina Bay&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-02.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;half&quot; alt=&quot;Sentosa&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-03.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;half&quot; alt=&quot;Garden by the Bay&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-04.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, other than learning the startup methodology, I also visited a ton of places in Singapore, Night Safari, Garden by the Bay, Sentosa, Raffle Places, Clarke Quay, best rooftop bar &lt;a href=&quot;http://travel.cnn.com/singapore/drink/best-singapore-rooftop-bars-197848&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1-Altitude&lt;/a&gt;, Little India, Orchard Road, Bugis, what a shame I didn’t get to Chinatown lol! I found Singapore to be a very lovely place, it is extremely small but ridiculously diverse, from Indians to Chinese to Malays to Westerners, you could expect everything there. From the riverside bars in Clarke Quay and Raffle Places to the outdoor ones on Orchard Road, I could say working short-term in Singapore is totally preferable to Hong Kong, but in terms of living permanently, I’m not too sure because things to do will run out pretty soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other observations from my trip were that the architectures in the city are consistent with the similar modern touch, taxi drivers are very friendly and like to talk with the passengers, asking me whether hong kong girls are prettier looking. I have also had most of my meals at the hawker centers or food court, the food there is so cheap that I had to order two sometimes, but the quality? so-so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can now announce that Singapore has jumped onto my favorite list of cities right behind Bangkok and Taipei. To be honest, it is quite an ideal city to work overseas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Garden by the Bay&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-05.jpg&quot; class=&quot;half&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Boat Quay&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-06.jpg&quot; class=&quot;half&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Garden by the Bay&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-07.jpg&quot; class=&quot;half&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Little India&quot; src=&quot;https://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/kevoncheung-blog/20130326-singapore-08.jpg&quot; class=&quot;half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/crushing-customer-development-in-singapore</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/crushing-customer-development-in-singapore</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-03-26T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Silly Low Paying Tech Jobs in Hong Kong</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I came across a job search site, and given I have decided to dive into a geeky path, so I clicked into the site to see whether there will be a future for being a tech guy in the Hong Kong industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to my surprise, the first thing I noticed was the extremely low paying monthly salary ranging from HK$8,000 to $12,000 (that is about US$1,000 to $1,500 a month) as a web developer or designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What struck me hard was that these jobs require specialized skill, at least not everyone could become a person capable of working with HTML, CSS, PHP and SQL in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so what is the reason that they still get paid so little working six days a week? Why are employers still offering a salary that anyone could barely survive with in Hong Kong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became curious about this matter because a few weeks ago I applied to Dev Bootcamp in San Francisco. DBC is an intense program that will teach Ruby on Rails in 9 weeks, and on average graduates get paid US$80,000 annually for being an entry level developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmm…using my middle school math, that’s US$6,666 a month, almost four and a half times higher than working in Hong Kong. Just a few months of intense programming and anyone will “definitely” get a much better pay about 8,000 miles away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started pondering, are the jobs really that different in HK and in SanFran? Is it the culture? Is it the boss?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my point of view, culture stands as a huge differentiator in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competitive environment forces young people in Hong Kong to underestimate the value of their work, thus lowering their own expectations of salary. They tend to believe they have “no say” over what they are offered, and if they don’t take the job, someone will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scenario makes it so easy for the employer to just stick with a low paying salary because eventually, a young man in bad financial shape will step into the shoe of this job and be willing to take the job with that amount of money. With this salary level, most of the jobs even require working on Saturday, which is totally ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, a lot of business owners in Hong Kong pay more attention on the numbers (profit and cost) over the quality of working in a team (personality, motivation, company culture).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have interned in startups before, and the environment of startups is not far different from a normal small business. Everyone gets there around 9:30am, sits in front of their computers, and occasionally hold meetings. Though it is better, it is still too much like a traditional business without the fun and energy a startup should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employers look for the cheapest possible labor to do the job, and the overall culture and how happy this guy will be? Screw it, not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the majority of the industry (mostly fresh graduates from local universities) remain silent with the money they get paid, then the payroll will never be able to rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a whole system of people to make an impact, and it is a very difficult task. This is just what I feel about most tech jobs in town, I might be wrong because I’m extremely new to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I will see more upside rooms and potentials leading up to successful stories in the near future in my own land.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/silly-low-paying-tech-jobs-in-hong-kong</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/silly-low-paying-tech-jobs-in-hong-kong</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-02-25T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>2013 Resolutions</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;From my other post from last night, well technically this morning, I set up some 2013 resolutions for myself in the area of traveling and going out at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m gonna add more in this post to review at the end of this year how many of those I achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of times I will have goals like “keep a regular gym routine”, and I figure those generic goals never worked. Therefore, I’m going to go with some specific ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will stick to my front page so that I can remind myself from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No traveling until summer. If Sponfed is doing well with stable income, one trip is allowed;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No more Macau in 2013;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going out only once every two weeks;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Join a public competition - February 24, 2013 Standard Chartered Marathon 10km &lt;span style=&quot;color: #f15a29; font-weight: bold&quot;&gt;(finished in 57:42)&lt;/span&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master in Ruby on Rails and build at least two web applications on my own;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master in HTML5 and CSS3;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn about a new friend’s life or career story per month;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read at least one book a month;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/2013-resolutions</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/2013-resolutions</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-01-13T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>It Is Why And How You Do It That Matters</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night, I had an amazing dinner with my family at this restaurant called SiChuan Da Ping Huo. Obviously a very spicy place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was it so amazing? Because the food was spicy and yummy and the price was beyond reasonable. For HKD$320 (+10%) per person, you get to enjoy the authentic sichuan cuisine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part was the use of simple ingredient such as eggplant, potato, and tofu to create the dishes. Da Ping Huo brought out the best side of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, and I realized a restaurant can really relate to business or startup (because restaurant is a business of course haha). Having luxurious ingredients is like having a brilliant business idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become a popular restaurant, it is not plainly just serving wagyu beef or shark fin to your customers, it is the way you cook and the love chef and staff together put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same concept applies to a startup, having the most brilliant idea does not guarantee you success and fame. Everything got to start small and grow as time goes, it is how much effort you put in and how well the execution is. Value of what it is is far less important to how it is and why it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This What-How-Why reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action.html&quot;&gt;an inspiring talk by Simon Sinek&lt;/a&gt;, who conveyed a powerful marketing technique to all of us. When we try to bring out a message, we should always start with Why, then How, then What. Tell people why you want to do this and spread the message emotionally. Definitely worth checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/it-is-why-and-how-you-do-it-that-matters</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/it-is-why-and-how-you-do-it-that-matters</guid>
                <pubDate>2012-10-21T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Failure, So What?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Since graduated about four and a half months ago, I have been planning on a path towards entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard a wide range of advice along the way, some suggesting me to get “real experience” first, others, about my age, would praise how bold I am. Right, I have chosen the path where failure happens quite frequently, and lots of people do give up after awhile, but this path presents lots of learning opportunities for a fresh grad like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to name a few things I’ve already done or learned in the past few months: talking to endless strangers, networking, getting advice and feedback on a new business concept, evaluating the pros and cons of different approaches to business decisions, meeting potential partners and learning how to read who’s a good guy and who’s a bad guy, learning how to prioritize things and doing the important ones first….. bla bla bla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list can easily go on and on, yet my passion and motivation will fuel me for the more stuff thats coming. After about a month of soft launch, the business is still raw and undeveloped. It does take time to create something, don’t let failure stop you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>https://kevoncheung.com/failure-so-what</link>
                <guid>https://kevoncheung.com/failure-so-what</guid>
                <pubDate>2012-10-18T14:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
